[Music]
in
for
[Music]
[Applause]
e
welcome living Mana church family we are
so happy to have you here with us today
worshiping with the living Mana Church
it is such a blessing to have you each
and every week but we are just so
thankful that you are here today if this
is your first time worshiping with
living Mana Church please put a one in
the chat and tell us where you are
viewing from we want to say a very
special welcome to you and to the rest
of you that are our normal visitors and
members thank you for always coming and
supporting living Mana church let us
know where you're viewing from so we can
say a welcome and where you are watching
from it's always exciting to see that I
see we have Michelle from Portland
Oregon welcome welcome it's good to see
you here uh Michelle in that beautiful
um C country state of Oregon it actually
Portland I wanted to say something about
Portland I believe I believe that
Portland is probably one of the
prettiest cities in America when I
visited Portland I it was I thought it
was the most beautiful city to have the
river that runs through it it's
absolutely gorgeous if you haven't been
there you have to go okay and Shannon
from Elmont New York welcome to living
Mana Church always good to see you
sister Lynette always good to see you
hear your voice when you sing and you're
coming in from new yor York so it's
always a blessing to see you welcome
welcome welcome we have my dear sweet
friend Candice from
Detroit oh Candace how I miss you we had
so much fun this summer um and turkey
and in and in Israel it was truly a fun
trip so I'm just happy to see you here
such a good friend that's awesome Jerry
from San Diego another beautiful city I
have to say San Diego is a beautiful
city as well so Jerry welcome welcome
and happy Sabbath to all of you I
haven't seen any ones yet but they may
they may be coming so please continue to
put in the chat where you are viewing
from we are happy that you are all here
today just want to give you a few
announcements that um this week mental
health Monday we are not having mental
health Monday this week but Dr Ricardo
white and myself we will be back the
following Monday the following Monday so
make sure that you tune in for that and
look out for the text alerts to let you
know the top topic and you can even
follow our social media speaking of that
if you don't follow living Mana Church
on Instagram please do because not only
do you get uh we you know especially
Sabbath information we uh let you know
there like the topic and the speaker and
different things that are going on with
living Mana church so please follow us
on Instagram um because you can keep up
with the church that way the best way to
keep up with the church is to sign up to
get the text messages and alerts and so
we want to show you how to do that at
this this time you just have to text LM
o to
84576 and that signs you up to get the
text alerts that's if you're here in
America if you are if you live
internationally and you're not in the
United States then you uh need to sign
up for Mighty networks because Mighty
networks also gives you the information
uh that is needed you're able to get
messages from the church that way as
well and it really is a powerful way to
stay connected Ed uh to the church
because we are an online only that means
we're not in person at all church that
staying connected in these various ways
is so very important so you want to make
sure that you sign up to get those text
alerts also um even though mental health
Mondays will not be here this week true
Health Tuesday will be and so I believe
this Pro this week's program is going to
be Dr schelp so he's hosting so you
definitely want to tune in for that we
have the power Wednesdays which is like
it just says it's powerful each and
every Wednesday to bring your request to
hear the testimonies of answered prayer
it is such a blessing to fellowship with
the living Mana church family during a
midweek service so you definitely want
to tune in to that and on Thursdays
we've been having money matters and uh
our answers all things I should say it
does matter but it answers all things
with Don Daniels and it has been a
blessing I know so many of you have been
excited about that um the viewing
numbers have been going up and up and up
with that program so we praise we praise
God that it's been such a blessing so
please share with your friends let them
know that living man a church the church
you attend we care about all the aspects
of your life we care about your mental
your physical your spiritual your prayer
life your financial life we care about
the whole we are a whole listic uh
Ministry in church so we care about it
all so definitely share the different
programs that we have available we're
not just here on Sabbath uh but
definitely share uh the Sabbath messages
and the sermons that are here that come
on here at Living Mana church with your
friends and your families your
co-workers whoever you think will be
blessed by this information speaking of
that looking forward to Pastor Meyer's
sermon today it's going to be a true
blessing um I've heard little pieces of
it um and I'm just going to let you know
that it will it's going to be
transforming your prayer life that's all
I'm going to say so definitely stay
tuned uh so that you will definitely be
blessed by Pastor Meyer's sermon today
but we have before that happens we have
a special Sabbath school program
prepared for you we have invited uh
Sister Janet Abby back with us we're
going to be talking about Outreach uh to
our communities and because we are a
virtual church and our church uh
viewership and membership is all around
the world and so we're going to be
talking about different ways different
ideas that you guys have brought up to
do uh Outreach because we're having our
Outreach Sabbath on September 18th so
just for those of you who were not tuned
in last week September 18th is our
Outreach Sabbath what does that mean
that means we will not be here in studio
that's right we're we're encouraging
everyone everyone uh that supports and
loves living Mana church this is our
time to go and to out and to reach the
world to go out and be the hands and
feet of Jesus and do and and bless
someone else so we're not g to be here
eating uh the food for ourselves the
spiritual food for ourselves we're going
to be offering uh literal food in some
cases and spiritual food and be a
blessing to others on that Sabbath and
so we're going to talk all about that
today uh with Sister Janet Abby and so
we can get to hear some of your ideas
maybe give you some ideas and and just
what that Ministry really looks like and
why it's such a blessing and why we're
doing this uh be um and the way that
this is just what God has called us to
do to be a blessing to others in this
way so we're going to talk about that
and then after uh we talk about that
with sister Abby we're going to have
some of our prayer team uh leadership on
and we're going to talk about the
blessings and the power of prayer you're
not going to want to miss that you want
to ignite your prayer life you want to
see miracles happen you're going to want
to stay tuned to see what our prayer
some leaders in our prayer team are
talking about so before we jump in with
uh sister Abby we are going to just say
a word of prayer and thank God for his
Sabbath and the blessings that it brings
so if you could please bow your heads
with me as we
pray Heavenly Father Lord we thank you
again for this sabbath we thank you for
all the viewing audience that is
watching from all around the world Lord
we just Praise You For Living Mana
church and the way that you have raised
it up in what you're doing with this
church and how it's touching people's
lives Lord we pray that you will just
bless uh this time together today as we
worship bless our conversation as we
talk about doing Outreach um here all
around the world on November 18th and so
we just ask for your blessings in Jesus
name amen so at this time I want to
invite uh Sister Janet Abby to the
program looking forward to talking hey
good I was gonna say well good morning
for you good afternoon for me and
whatever time it is where everybody else
welcome thank you good to be here with
you hi sis it's also very formal yeah I
know I know because we're friends too
but I I'm over here calling you sister
Abby that's okay that's okay I'm really
excited to be here today at tante it's
great to be back again um as you know as
you mentioned you know our Outreach
Sabbath November 18th we are super
excited about this a ton and I have been
texting a little emoji to each other
this week as we're watching the plans
coming into fruition so we're really
excited because you know we really just
see as aton's already mentioned the
importance of creating opportunities for
our living manner friends and our living
man members to be out there talking to
talking to the world about a God who
cares about their needs you know so this
is this is really exciting for us to to
be able to have this opportunity you
know I was thinking about what you were
just saying at tante and we at Living
Manet we are so incredibly blessed
because almost every day of the week we
are fed like you said with the most
nourishing and wholesome spiritual food
right it is I don't know if it really
gets better than what we have here at
Living mana and so we've been we're fed
you know every day with this incredible
spiritual food but even you know one of
our our health professionals will tell
us that if we eat and we just eat no
matter how good the food is if we eat
too much be GL gluttonous yes become
spiritually obese right we that's what's
going to happen if we if we just only
eat this incredible no matter how good
the food is it's not going to be good
for us spiritually if we just eat and
sit and sleep and eat and sit and sleep
right and so we understand the
importance of creating a healthy
spiritual balance in our lives because
even with this great food that and this
great spiritual nourishment that we're
getting you know our spiritual archeries
get blocked right and then the nutrient
that needs to get to our hearts can't
get to our hearts and we're at risk of a
spiritual heart attack right and I say
that because we we then kind of lose or
we forget the importance of sharing and
serving others right and our hearts not
that our hearts become cold yes we're on
fire because we're having all this
hearing this great word and having all
this great um spiritual nourishment but
if we forget what we're supposed to do
with it we're in we are at risk of a
spiritual heart attack and so we at
Living Mana we're very much aware that
we want to we want our our our church
Community to be involved with the whole
mission right to to go not just to sit
and to eat but to go right and to share
as I said with this Lost World help them
to understand that there's a God who
really cares about their needs and so
November 18th is what we're going to be
doing you know at tante this week alone
we served so um with I you know little
plug but I'm a CO and founder of a an
organization nonprofit organization call
stand for and we do a plethora of
different um ways of serving our
community but one of the things that we
do is um food security we address food
security and this week Al between Sunday
and Wednesday we served eight no sorry
700 families with food 700 families wow
right which was you know that's a record
in just a few days right and if you
times that by four there's about an
average of four people per family if you
times that by four that's a lot of
people that we' served right thousands
of people that we've served with food
but one thing that I was thinking of I
was thinking about coming and talking to
you today of ton that when you see these
lines and lines of people lining up for
food you have to understand that their
needs are multi-layered right so they're
coming if they're willing to wait two
hours for food right then they must have
other needs there will be other needs
maybe rent would be a situation for some
of these families maybe you know just
hygiene basic hygiene items might be or
school fees or you know furniture or you
know just or health will probably be an
issue for a lot of these families so
there are so many multiple needs that
people have when you see them coming for
one thing the likelihood is their needs
will be multiple multi-layered and so
what I'm saying at tante is this is our
time shine is right I'm not saying shine
so we get the glory but shine so we
reflect God's character there are so
many needs out there in our community
that we get hundreds of texts and emails
and Facebook posts of people please we
need food can you help us please we need
this can you help us and so we are
positioned living man of church to have
this Global Network of people to be able
to touch the world in an in a unique way
and to do this um in a way that will
help people really understand the heart
of God and yes I I agree wholeheartedly
that you know it's it's really doing
what Jesus did like he came to this
world to share the gospel but he did so
much in meeting the Practical needs of
people that's how that's how they like
that's when people said okay I trust
him Christ alone right Christ Christ
methods alone absolutely because you
know if you think about and I know in
the I'm not saying in the past because
we still do this now as a means of reach
of evangelism giving people glow tracks
and books well there's nothing wrong
with that but that doesn't feed a hungry
person right right it doesn't keep
somebody warm on the street right and so
if we are intentional about doing the
doing our Outreach the way or reaching
the world the way Jesus did then you
know he gave us the model that we are
supposed to follow right and we mingle
with them as one who desired their good
we meet their needs and then when we've
done that we say come follow me right
yes we follow me so we have a unique
opportunity and S what I do also and I
knowon and I feel very much the same
about this this is not a one time like
once a year event right right it's not
like Christmas and Thanksgiving yes yes
we want our members to be doing um some
type of Outreach through we want this to
become a lifestyle um so some type of
Outreach um throughout the year and you
come up with your personal way that you
think you can help others so it may not
look like um what your ministry is doing
Janet it may not like where you're
feeding um the the the those who are you
know incure with food or it may look a
little bit differently or a lot
differently but you and God come up with
what you're supposed to be doing in your
area absolutely and people mentioned
some different ones last week and I
thought thought they were great great
ideas helping single moms um maybe just
with babysitting um if you're if you're
familiar with a a single mom that you
have a good relationship with and um
there might you might be able to offer
um that um I think you had mentioned
Janet last week about you know mowing
somebody's lawn that is not physically
able but their lawn needs to be mow like
the neighborhood can see it like it's
things are overgrown or you know just
practical things practical things that
can also be and and you're absolutely
right Aton it doesn't have to be a big
organized event it doesn't have to you
know you don't even need to go and
volunteer at another organization there
are needs all around you on your street
in your neighborhood and even in our
local churches on the ground or even
here at our living Mana church we we
understand there are needs that we can
meet you know uh there's you know so
many different ideas and I'll just run
through just some of the you know some
of the the ideas that we're talking
about so you know it's Thanksgiving
right so this is a time for food and
family and there they're going to be a
number of families who you know at this
time of the you know this time of the
year it's difficult for them to be able
to have those resources to make meals so
you could invite someone over to your
house for lunch right or for for
Thanksgiving and it doesn't only have to
be
Thanksgiving um you know we talked about
seniors cutting their grass this is a
really challenging task you've ever
tried to mow you know a lawn or cut the
grass it's not something that our senior
people will find easy do so you know
this is and this is if you're young and
willing and strong this will be such a
great way to meet the needs for our
senior community to create a nice space
for them to be in and you know fruit
baskets take healthy fruit you could
take that to them you know if you have
children and they want to get involved
you could have them make a a card for
them you know the the senior would be
just so appreciative that somebody's
thinking about them right yes yes you
don't know how far that actually goes I
mean we have so many that people who are
seniors that are alone um or even like
people who are are widows or have lost
their husband or their wife I yeah I can
tell you I mean my mom is um you know
she lost her husband um so she's you
know been alone as far as you know and
so if someone you know offered to to to
come over and to you know do something
some outside work at her home I know she
would would would love that and probably
give them um a nice little meal as I
think a thank you just because they're
doing that for her but just you know
just making connections uh with people
who are in elderly or in their senior
years and they're alone or what for
whatever the the case may be it it means
so much to them it means so much to them
it really does and we have in Mountain
buo there's an RV community that we're
connected to we work with that RV
community and you know the the person in
charge of that particular organization
said sometimes people just want to they
want company you know just go and talk
to them especially our seniors right so
even if you don't have anything to give
you can give your time right just
conversation just visit in to see how
you are right did these small little
these small little acts of kindness
really go a long way and they really
open the door for us to talk to them
about this Jesus who loves them right
and to show them who he is as we reflect
his character and then you were
mentioning um oh and doing their
shopping that's a good one too offering
to go and just pick up their groceries
for them that's that's that's you know
that's that would be a really good one
for them to walk and carry bags it's
it's really difficult it can be it can
be I want to comment on um Veronica
rodri said Outreach for the Youth
they're slipping through the cracks and
I have to say the reason why I'm
highlighting that comment is um because
taking our youth out or getting our
youth and young adults involved in
Outreach can be so amazing and
lifechanging to them to do ministry in
this way because they're not just coming
to church or City Pew are just ignoring
Church altogether because they're just
like tired and bored of it but they're
actually being active and they're
changing people's lives in real time
like they see the reactions absolutely I
can say that you know Janet and I used
um used to be a part of a Ministry well
um that that used to have young adults
and youth or youth um going out to do
ministry in this way and to see the
reaction and how happy and excited they
were to be able to just be out helping
people um was just an amazing thing to
see and I have to say for me personally
like my favorite sabbaths are these type
of sabbaths these Outreach sabbaths
they're the biggest blessing and for our
youth and for us as well yeah and I
would agree with that you know um part
of what our organization does we we we
disciple young people particularly in
fact I would probably say like 70 to 80%
of our volunteers who work with us are
young people high school kids or or
young adults and that's in the nonprofit
and also in the church setting and um it
really does make a difference to their
Christian experience I remember at tante
when we first started um like the hate
Ministry I was with your husband uh
about eight years ago I think it was and
in it started might have been a little
bit it might have been almost 10 eight
maybe nine maybe nine okay but at least
at least eight at at least well yeah it
could be yeah it could be and I remember
um the re one of the reasons why that
Ministry um came to fruition because I
remember one time I was at my house and
uh I was a Youth and Young Adult leader
for my local church and the Youth and
Young adults came to me and said Miss
Janet we are so tired of doing Church
the regular way we're tired of just
talking about what it means to be a
Christian and praying about it and
reading about it and listening to
sermons what we want to do is we want to
get out into the community and address
some of these issues that are plaguing
our local communities we want to be a
part of the change right so I was blown
away by that and uh you know I'm like
okay then let's do it and so we started
the ministry which was like the hate
Ministry that your husband and your
children and yourself were all a part of
and it was such a powerful ministry here
in the bay I remember the first do you I
don't know if you were I remember we
hundred young people showed up to go to
do Outreach you remember that first one
we went to the police station absolutely
it
First Responders and and from then it
just grew and in fact my nonprofit it
was actually it came out of that
Ministry because we were expanding at
such a rate that we we recognized that
we needed to find new ways to get
resources so it came out of that so in
fact that it was that Mothership for for
Stan for but the the point is that young
people this generation of young people
they they want to change the world they
want to impact the world you know I
speak to them I work with them I speak
for them all the time and the energy
amongst the young people in the church
and also outside of the church but this
generation of young people they don't
want to just be passive and see all
these these uh social issues going on
around them they want to be a part of
addressing them so if we can create
opportunities for our young people to be
out in the community doing and
addressing real needs that is going to
change the way they experience their
Christian their Christian walk so I
thank you so much for that comment it's
a it's it's so very true um and yes so
at Living Mana we've got to find a way
to get our young people involved and I
know talking to Our Youth and Young
Adult Pastor um uh uh loami we've been
talking about this so he and I are
already got some plans in place he's got
some great plans for the Youth and Young
Adult Ministry which I'm super excited
about we we are very excited working
together with that so thank you for that
comment great great comment yes also I
think this is a great time to just share
that well I want to see how many of you
have already ordered your living Mana
t-shirts for your Outreach Sabbath just
put a one in the chat um and for those
of you who were not here for the
announcement or if you're not signed up
to get notifications and so you did not
get the link to the t-shirt we want to
talk talk about that so we discussed
last week possibly having living Mana
t-shirts or hoodies where we can that
have living Mana church and on the back
it says Outreach and you can get it
actually you can choose and get it
customized to how you what you want it
um to say Outreach or no Outreach but
it's gonna say living Mana Church um and
so you can customize that but you're
going to be able to to go out and do
your Outreach and be uh representing God
number one but also let them know that
you are part of this online community
this church this ministry living Mana
church so let's see I don't know okay
somebody said I have okay so some of you
are saying you've you've gotten your
T-shirt so those who are did not uh get
the link um through a text message or
they weren't here last week last week to
hear us talking about it we want I think
the link is in the chat now there's a
link there now in the chat but we're
also going to put the QR code up so that
you can scan the QR code and if it's um
if it's not Sabbath in the part of the
world that you are in at this time you
can go ahead and go to that if it's
still Sabbath you can wait till it's not
Sabbath uh but definitely You're Gonna
Want to if you want to have a t-shirt or
a hoodie to go out and do your Outreach
um on November 18th and if you want to
be wearing that you need to get these
items you need to try to order these
items uh no later than than Monday uh or
Tuesday I think at the very latest so
that they can ship to you um so you'll
be able to pick it up so I think the QR
code it's there it's on the screen so
please scan that so that you can get
your your gear your your merchandise I
think it's so exciting that we we you
know that we're able to have people go
out in the shirts because once we meet
the needs of these people and they are
often times when we go out there inquire
so what organization are you from or
where are you know why are you doing
this and so if we have the living manner
shirts we can direct them here so they
can not only have those physical needs
but but also those spiritual needs met
as well so this is a really great
opportunity um for us to be able to kind
of balance the spiritual and the
physical needs as we go out into the
community so what color T-shirt are you
going to wear at tante because I know we
have a whole array of different colors
can choose from I know I like I think I
don't I think I like the baby blue I
think the baby blue I liked that one um
I also like the the off-white the cream
the tan color I like that one as well so
I yes I know I haven't actually chosen
but I will choose by tonight or tomorrow
yes you should choose but the thing is
you have we have such a great array of
different colors so you can choose one
that suits you um um but it would be
great for us all being un as it gets
colder as you want to keep going out
there and serving on behalf of living
Mana then make sure you get your hoodies
too they're really great price not too
expensive uh so make sure you get your
hoodies to keep you warm as you go out
there and serve and so we just want to
just very quickly as we're talking about
often times when we talk about going out
into the community first things we think
about is homeless Ministry so as you do
go out um to feed or to take resources
or to just minister to our home
Community we're just asking that you do
that with care and caution that you
first of all we treat these people with
dignity whoever we're serving we treat
them with dignity and respect and
understand that they are human beings
right just because they're in a less
fortunate situation than we might be it
doesn't mean that we should remove uh
the dignity in in terms of how we're
treating them or um and so um let's just
be mindful of that also it it can be
unpredictable situations when you're
going into homeless encampments or
homeless communities it it it can be um
unpredictable there is a lot of mental
health issues there so we're just asking
that if you're going out into these
communities please make sure that you go
with a group don't go in small groups of
one or two I would say make sure that
you take a team with you if that's what
you're planning to do um and you know
and if it is um an organized Community
make make sure that you speak to
whoever's in charge don't just kind of
because this is their home right this is
where they live these are their
possessions and their belongs and to us
it may not look like you know it might
even look like trash or whatever but to
them it's not so we just have to be
mindful of these things when we go into
these communities and just some quick
ideas of we talked about it last week
but just in case there's somebody here
today who wasn't here last week some of
the things that you can take for our for
our um unsheltered brothers and sisters
is you can make hot meals it's getting a
little cold now um you know when we went
out just a couple of weeks back they're
telling us you know do do you have any
blankets it's getting cold at night so
blankets and pillows uh are great you
know to to take to um to unsheltered
communities hygiene items uh socks
underwear um beanies and gloves to keep
them warm we talked about underwear last
time as being a real need
you know they don't very rare sometimes
not even ever do these to you know does
this community get a chance to shower
and change so um underwear and socks
will be great and things like that um
and then sanitary towels we talked about
that for for the women who are out there
that's just such a I can imagine that's
just just such a huge need so you know
if you can you know if you're able to
access or you're able to purchase or
share you know some of these sry items
would be really a great need and torches
if you have torches it's dark in th
those places you know a lot of the
encampments and I'm not sending you to
the encampments I'm Just sh kind of just
sharing experiences when you walk
through those encampments in the daytime
there's no there's no light so I can
imagine what it's like at night so
torches would be a great thing to um to
to share with um a homeless community
and then also the tarps that they use
for shelter um tarps are also a great
need um and then we talked about dog
food as also something that we generally
don't think about but there a lot of um
homeless people who have emotional
support animals which are generally dogs
and so when you go out there there's
dogs running all over the place and
they're so skinny and frail looking and
so you know often times if they can't
afford to feed themselves they're likely
that they'll be able to feed their pets
so you know dog food would be a great um
a great way to meet the needs of our
holess community um and yeah so I don't
know if there's anybody else who has any
other ideas or any thoughts or questions
before before we um before we tie up any
any
thoughts yeah I see um I see Gigi said
if you're tied on a budget you can get
shower shoes for one or two dollars
which are so very uh needed in and
overlooked items in shelters in shelters
yeah that's a really good one actually
yeah I think we have a few a good few
boxes of those that's a really good idea
I didn't think about that Gigi so I know
we do have maybe half a palette of those
so I maybe we'll donate them to a
shelter thank you for that it's a great
great idea great idea yes we want to I
know you had mentioned this last week
about you know in a um like in a
respectful uh way to if you can get like
a picture of of you doing the Outreach
not to bring glory to yourself but just
something that we could like share on
the website or just share here on living
man Church on some of the areas and or
things that you did do um in Ministry
and Outreach just to encourage others
yeah I think it's also important though
which I didn't mention last week is to
ask permission right just don't just
take photographs of people with without
asking permission correct I think that's
really important to do that and it is
important you can take pictures of
yourself out there with your resources
ready to go um but we really it's really
important that we treat anybody that
we're serving we don't want to be a
opportunist but you know because all the
good that we'll do will will will not
you know will kind of the enemy against
us all right and yes and SMS um said
hand warmers and because it's getting
cold I think it's a great great idea
especially I remember many many years
ago I went to this very large event and
that was it was on the East Coast it was
in the Maryland area and it was outside
and the hand warmers were everything
because you can just put them in your
like the pockets of your hoodie the
front part put the hand warmers and keep
your keep your hands warm um or try to
keep your hands warm and so those are
really can be really really um important
when you're when you're in the cold and
in the elements abut um just trying to
look at these um comments but but yeah
so people are having some good ideas I
think they're excited want want you guys
to remember that on the 18th we're not
having church as normal we are shutting
down to give you an opportunity to spend
the Sabbath to go out and help others
and again you're coming up with the idea
because every this is a worldwide church
and so we live in different areas with
people have different situations we're
just it's all different so it's going to
be catered to cater to tailor made for
you and to what you can do in the area
um that you know suits your situation
also if you didn't catch us just a
little while ago and you're just tuning
in if you want to get a t-shirt or a a
hoodie a living Mana t-shirt or a hoodie
for your Outreach uh Sabbath you can
scan the QR code that you see it's it's
right above Janet's
head you can scan that c that QR code um
and that will take you to the links
where you can get your T-shirt or hoodie
or both um and you're G to want to do
that by I say Monday at the latest um I
think maybe possibly Tuesday you can um
order some just be for shipping to give
it time to get to you um is I think
that's really important um that's if you
want to do that if you don't want to get
any t-shirt you want to just go out and
you're you don't you don't have to but
it's it's available to you if you would
like to wonderful yes so we're excited
this is our second time doing this uh
we'd like to and we don't and again what
Janet said we don't want it to be like
oh I just do Outreach Ministry when the
church shuts down and we do Outreach
Sabbath no we want you to do Outreach
like we said we want to become part of
your lifestyle so that's why it's so
important that you create something that
is tailor made for you and works for you
and the area that you live in and you
can be as you and God can be as creative
as you need to be because you guys know
your situation and other people that are
in your surrounding their situation so
we are excited we're excited absolutely
and remember that you know people have
needs every day of the week you know
often times we want to save our Outreach
for sth because it's convenient for us
right right but people have needs every
day of the week so you know it might be
an idea to keep something in your car
that if you see a homeless person or you
you
that you can just immediately
immediately be able to address that need
you know let's be always thinking about
always thinking we used to yes we there
was a member at our church when we were
in California um that she gave she gave
me this idea but it was just a little
bag a s well a little Ziploc bag about
this big and you could put a pair of
thick socks um some toothpaste a
toothbrush travel you know some you know
now now hand sanitizer stuff like that
for
women you know some of those items and
so just having it in your car because
when we were in California and San Jose
I mean there's homeless people
everywhere sometimes just stop at a I
recently learned that there's around a
thousand just in San Jose just in the
city of San there's a
thousand yes so you can just you know
run into someone anywhere and just you
know that that you can say hey I have
this baggie for you and it has some of
the essential things that uh they are
most likely in need of and so uh there's
so many different things that you can do
but just to consider you know like Janet
said any they're they they in need all
throughout the week not just on Sabbath
and so you can always have that prepared
and ready to go so once again we are so
excited about SE um I I keep do I keep
thinking September November 18 November
18th we're excited about that uh for the
Outreach Sabbath and just so you can
sign up I want to put a away where we
can stay connected with you so you can
get all the updates and stuff that we're
doing I just want to remind you on how
you can sign up to get texts from living
Mana church because if we have any
updates about our Outreach Sabbath
you're going to see it here so we're
just gonna put that up so just text
LMC if you haven't already signed up to
84576 and that way we can stay connected
with you living Mana church can stay
connected and send you information that
um that you may need pertaining to the
November 18th Outreach Sabbath and so
again pray about what God wants you to
do and we are just excited uh to do this
um as a church around the world and just
to be service to others so um we just
want to thank Janet for coming back on
and encouraging us and talking about
these things
uh we just want to say a word of prayer
just because I know people are thinking
and praying about what they're going to
do and how they're going to allow God to
use them so let's bow our heads again as
we pray Heavenly Father Lord we thank
you for the opportunity for November
18th it will be such a blessing as
living Mana church members all around
the world will be doing Outreach in in
different ways and trying to just help
others and with their practical needs
Lord we I pray that everyone who wants
to go out that you will put um what you
want them to do on their heart Lord and
that they will be obedient to that and
that it will be such a blessing when
they do that and so we just ask all
these things in the precious name of
Jesus amen amen amen amen well thank you
Janet and we will we will see you
again we will see you again happy
Sabbath to you by okay bye bye and to
all of you that are viewing we are not
done yet that was just the first first
half of our Sabbath school program we
are now going to move into prayer we're
going to have our prayer a few of our
prayer leaders come on I'd like to
invite uh Terry soel and Gina yes hi oh
okay all right I got Amar hi and Amar hi
hi hi good to see you guys all right so
it's just okay is it just you guys today
and that's fine if it is because I'm
always thrilled to see you okay nope
there he goes there it
go yes welcome everyone welcome welcome
welcome I'm gonna let you guys introduce
yourselves well Terry and Amar we
already know you but go we know but but
I'm gonna let you introduce yourselves
too just for those who may not know who
you are so just very quickly very
briefly introd I want to each to
introduce themselves very quickly and
briefly because we want to get into the
heart of the matter so go ahead Gina or
Ross you can go
I'm I'm Ross Browns my bride
Gina welcome welcome okay okay and you
are Le you are part of the leadership of
our living Mana prayer team yep yes yes
and we
are we are so thankful for you guys all
right and the lovely couple the next
couple tell us well obviously we're
we're we're uh Terry and am you all know
us we love y'all you know Ross and gin
you said brief so they really kept it to
yep real brief
well that that's good thank you Ross and
Gina because we really do want to talk
about prayer and the power of prayer
yeah but Ross and Gina Have Been
instrumental in the in the in The Prayer
Ministry from the very beginning they
were always active even before they
joined the leadership and now they're
overseeing the 24-hour prayer and
fasting and they're also facilitators on
power Wednesday I mean just involved in
everything so we praise God for them
they're they're a true blessing to us
yes we do we praise praise God for all
of you
and for Terry and Amar and all of the
prayer team and everything that they do
um I have to say like even I'll just
give a little testimony real quick be
before you continue I'm sorry Terry um
you know the prayer team is such a
blessing it truly truly is to to my
husband and to myself uh you know
personally it's just like last night we
were trying to make sure everything was
all prepared so that today would be such
a blessed Sabbath for all of you and you
would receive the blessing and the
technology because we're online right so
the technology was was doing its was
doing its thing and Satan had his finger
on it but you know God of course is more
powerful but who is the first person I
reach out to is the prayer team and I
was like and I just said hey can you
guys pray and they did even better they
prayed but they they actually jumped on
a Prayer call and prayed with me and
that was just so encouraging and I knew
after that call that God was going to
work it out and he absolutely did
because we're here live praise the Lord
so just so thankful for the prayer team
but Terry and Amar did you want to go
more into introducing what you do for
yeah just a little bit you know I I
really wanted to send a shout out to
Sister Janet you know we love Sister
Janet we when we work when we lived in
San Jose we worked a lot together with
some of the churches there in Campbell
that she was you know supplying you know
food and grocery store we did the
grocery drives on on Thanksgiving and
you know you told Sister Janet you she
she said if you're G to take pictures
always kind of ask permission you know
if if all the photographs were taken of
the work that this beloved sister does I
mean she does so much believe me a lot
and so I thank God for it and I just
want to say that prayer actually goes
hand inand with outrage you know so you
know because what they're doing a lot of
it you know the Bible says in 1 John 38
that Jesus Christ the son of God was
manifested in order that he might
destroy the works of the devil and what
we're seeing all the pain the Suffering
The homelessness the mental illness a
lot of the Mis uh you know uh Mis
unfortunate circumstances that people
find themselves in or just needing help
is the work of the devil it's not God's
plan for us it's God's plan for us to
live the Abundant Life and so when we're
at Jesus hands and feet out there the we
need the prayer support you know to be
uh working hand inand and just covering
them giving them air coverage as the
pastor say so we thank God that at
Living Mana whenever the prayer warriors
come on we give them the Sevenfold
mission of living Mana church and
Outreach is right there so we're
supplying air coverage for the Outreach
Ministry and then if I could just say
one more thing um you know we talked
about a lot of ideas and I I love
hearing everybody talk about all the
wonderful ideas it's amazing what comes
out you know the things that we can do
but I think our greatest ability when it
comes to outreach is simply our
availability yes am I Lord am I
available to you I love what sister
Jerry put in the chat in in the pre
service huddle she says you know Lord uh
uh my memories my my storage is empty
and I'm available to you and so if we
just empty ourselves of self and and
make ourselves available God will use us
absolutely yes he will he will and so
we're Yes again we're so excited about
how God is going to use uh the members
and the viewership of of living Mana
church as they go out on November 18th
and we're thankful for that opportunity
we're also so thankful for the
leadership that you and and and and and
Gina and Ross and and ammer provide as
Leaders of The Prayer Ministry and as I
tuned in this past uh Wednesday I
actually tuned in like about I think
about 15 minutes late because I had
another meeting I had to jump off and
then go into to our prayer service and
the prayer leaders there was different
prayer leaders that were highlighting um
different ways that they do their Prayer
Ministry and so I wanted uh you guys to
talk a little bit about that I'm even
going to share a little bit about uh
prayer Journal myself but I want you
guys to talk about some of the different
uh ways that some of the prayer
leadership was discussing how they uh do
their their Prayer Ministry and journey
um so please share with our our our
viewing audience what was shared during
our prayer service some of the
highlights amen that would be Ross and
Gina because they facilitated they
facilitated power Wednesday
and you know uh it's really you know our
prayer team our program coordinator
which is Sister Joanne Stevens is so
awesome in putting things together and
she works behind the scene you know true
prayer is really a Ministry of obscurity
we get to be seen a lot here at Living
Mana so we do praise God for that but
humbly we accept the responsibility but
Ross and Gina since you guys facilitated
I think you should probably uh lead out
in this all right well
we were uh trying to figure out how to
do something different so the Holy
Spirit gave me the idea that we should
just ask the prayer leadership several
of them what they thought of different
types of Prayer Ministry so I I asked
Joanne um who Terry was just talking
about who was so instrumental behind so
much stuff um about prayer walking and
she she she pointed out that her prayer
walking is more of prayer
driving and because where she lives it's
just kind of safer to to drive than to
take an area and walk through so she'll
drive through areas and and and SL
slowly and prays for the people in her
neighborhood
um and then uh for corporate prayer we
spoke about and this be a couple of
different things T shared this um it's
is a a person praying for a group
including themselves uh such as Daniel's
prayer in Daniel 9 or it can be a group
praying together over a particular
subject I I wanted to before you guys
even went to corporate pray I wanted to
highlight um something that you had
mentioned uh for the prayer walking and
how power ful that can be um we I my
husband was you know he pastored in a
conference in California for 21 22 years
the central California Conference and at
at about 10 years of that we had
leadership under uh Jerry and Janet
Paige and Janet Paige um I have to say
she was the the person that really
inspired me to get into prayer
journaling and I'll talk about that in a
little bit but but on top of that she
was also did a lot of uh prayer walking
and so they would have a prayer walk
before when camp meeting would start so
this was a special time that the prayer
team would meet and they would walk the
grounds of camp meeting before all the
people came and it was so powerful um
that during this these prayer walking
experiences um that there were times
like I think for three years for three
years we were like the only conference
that would would raise during camp
meeting over a million dollars for
evangelism specifically for evangelism
but during that during the prayer
walking is when those prayers would
happen that we that she would be praying
so many different prayers for the people
that would come and their spiritual
journey and their families and part of
that was praying for the evang
evangelism offering but doing prayer
walking around the campgrounds and year
after year God would bless and and the
Really the world church was amazed that
this one conference could raise um from
its members over a million dollars for
evangelism so I just want to say the
power of prayer walking can truly be a
blessing can truly be a blessing
yeah sorry go ahead G um this is
something that Ross and I do also so for
for health we like to walk and uh for
that Morning Light uh for health we're
we're doing that um and so we walk
around our neighborhood and pray for
each of the families that are there uh
you know when we see toys in the yard we
pray for the children that are there
yeah there's several churches in our
neighborhood um so we uh pray for those
churches also and the businesses that we
walk past it's interesting she mentions
that because the um before we came to
living Mana the church we transferred
from to living Mana is literally right
in the heart
of Spokane it's almost dead center it's
one of the roughest neighborhoods and
Jean and I first learned about prayer
walking from uh Ron Halverson Senor
and and Ron had come to town and he
would ask all of us um where's the
roughest toughest neighborhood and he'd
take us out walking those neighborhoods
and you know this is guy that bulleted
whiz by his head he was perfectly calm
and comfortable but you take him up into
the wood and an alute and he
died and so um that's where we kind of
uh um got the idea about the prayer
walking and we've done a lot of it just
ourselves and with other people in group
and stuff so prayer walking works
miracles it changes cities it changes
lives it's yes it's truly a blessing um
I want you guys to um also this is
something that was spoken about about at
uh Power Wednesday at the prayer service
was the 24hour prayer like I have to be
honest like I'm the pastor's wife right
and I didn't even know I mean I knew it
was happening but I didn't know all the
logistics and the time I just didn't
know everything about it so if I didn't
know all the things I'm sure our viewing
audience doesn't know exactly all about
the 24-hour prayer service time so I
want you guys anybody can share about
this but I want you guys to let our
audience know um what is available to
them and when this happens amen well I
can give you the history of it and how
it got going and then I since Ross and
Gina are now overseeing it um I'm sure
they can give you uh the breakdown of
how people can get on the list how we
kind of run things I think it's
beautiful the way they have it organized
um but I want to say hi to Trevor in the
chat he's saying hi but if I could just
back up just one second about this
prayer walking prayer walking is a great
way to help us understand that you know
what my times of intimacy with God are
not just restricted to my prayer closet
that's right Enoch walked with God and
so I can have an intimate walk with the
Lord you know yes I'm always talking
about prison y'all y'all know you know
in prison we get out there and walk
around that track a lot right right in
prison you better learn how to pray
while you're walking you know because
you gonna need to be alert you gon need
to have God guiding your steps and so I
thank God to come out and see that in
living Mana you know we have a prayer
team of people who are just have so much
revelation and experience with these
beautiful aspects of prayer so we can
give God praise for it or pray driving
we've done that as well I've had to pray
driving I mean Weir your eyes open you
know but yes we've done that as well and
speaking about prayer driving the
Warriors the living man of Prayer
Warriors know about that because while
we were getting um the living man of
prayer team established right in the
very beginning Amar and I were
transitioning from San Jose to to
further up in Northern California so I
was commuting 186 miles a day and at
that time the Lord brought me you know
just the perfect little angel to help me
uh and assist me in getting the prayer
team set up and that was Sister Gigi and
you guys hear me talk about sister gig
all the time you know so me and sister
gig we talked a lot we shared a lot we
you know just did Ministry ideas well at
that time when Gigi was doing all that
work gig was also having her own issues
that she wanted to have prayer about and
so we were praying about her marriage
and about her husband and so she and I
began to fast and pray for dayron and
you know we didn't want to make it a
prerequisite or you know or you know
something that the prayer team had to do
but we shared with them what we were
doing and so people just got on board
with us and started then the next thing
you know there were a lot of other
people telling us hey I've got the same
issue you guys are praying about to be
specific God gave us the sermon about uh
demonic activity and so that's what we
first started fasting and praying about
Jesus says in in Mark chapter 9 when he
dealt with uh uh the the man's son who
had a death and dumb Spirit when they
came from the mountain of
transfiguration he said that this kind
can come forth by nothing but prayer and
fasting so just standing on that promise
without getting into a whole lesson
about it we began to pray and fast and
then others begin to say Can my name be
added to the list can my name and it's
become what it is today I think Ross and
Gan are gonna tell you because it's
really uh yes tell us what it is today
Ross and Gina and how people can if they
feel like they'd like for you to pray
for them 24 hours how they can get
involved or how they can get their
prayer requests on the list so tell us
all about
it okay so I'll let Gina go first okay
uh we have uh okay first of all the the
24-hour prayer and fasting uh Team we
have a day a week that we pick and we
have Thursday evening to Friday evening
um that we anoint ourselves with oil we
fast um some people fast with food other
people uh fast with electronics or or
you know don't watch TV whatever they
decide to to do their fasting with for
that 24hour period we pray
over the names and now not just demonic
activity we now have 13
categories 13 the what are your
categories can you tell us um so we have
Divine protection ambivalence to God
ambivalence to God
addiction gender identity issues and
sexual
issues healing physical religious and
Trauma demonic oppress depression and
possession
discouragement mental health PTSD AU
all one colum yeah
marriage um domestic abuse
traveling homelessness and financial
problems a category for unknown when
somebody will call in or or send us a
text or an email and they just say um
put me on the 24 but they give us no
information to know where to put them
they go into the unknown category God's
got that okay okay and then uh false
gods and Witchcraft those are the
13 all right so so how well okay okay go
ahead and say what you're gonna say and
then I want to let the audience know how
they can send in their request to get
into any one of those categories amen
amen um yeah like brother Terry said it
started with one name and then when
brother Terry called me and said hey I
need you to take over I think we had a
total of like 35 names now we have over
400 wow it's 400 400 names over all of
the different categories some of them
overlap because there's like right cover
all of
them wow and we also have so for the
audience and everybody if you don't want
your name known you don't want a family
member known but you do need the the
situation known we have aliases assigned
to certain names as well can just say
yes I yes yes yes that's amazing I love
all the forethought that you guys have
put into this on how it's organized and
another thing is is this is extremely
confidential um if you're not part of
the prayer team you have not gone
through the
orientation you not allowed into this
because of extreme confidentiality the
sensitivity of everything yes I
understand yes yes that but everyone's
welcome but everybody's welcome but
there are there are steps that you have
to make to get the list and be able to
pray over it right it's a little bit of
training so that everybody
knows that
confidentiality I think that's important
I think that's important I mean I'm in
I'm involved in a field where
confidentiality is everything I mean
it's a legal thing too but people also
feel much more comfortable to open up uh
to be able to even ask for help because
sometimes people suffer alone because
they think you know I don't want other
people to know what I'm going through I
don't want people to know my business
don't suffer alone let's let's um you
know pour out your whatever you're going
through let's bring it to the the the
The Throne of God because he can he can
work on the situation tell our viewing
audience how they can connect
how where do they send these prayer
requests how can they how can we I don't
know after we're doing today I think
that 400 is gonna go bigger but how can
we make that
for how can we do that okay they can
send it to the prayer request
line yep go ahead
am live attention and if it's for the
24hour now you send all your prayer
crests to this but if it's for the
24hour where we think prayer and fasting
is the only thing that's going to work
just
specify in in your message for the
24hour we'll just need a first name and
then what it's for and whether you want
it to be an alias or not okay it's that
yeah and the logistics of the 24-hour
prayer chat so people are taking kind of
shifts right like is that how it works
yes yeah yes um so we went through and
we broke up the clock into
24 2hour
segments 12 sorry 12 two hour segments
so it covers 24 hours um in the
beginning uh my little brother Sean who
yall know uh what he would open at 900
PM Pacific and we would close at 900
p.m. Friday okay um since Sean has been
hospitalized I've taken over you can
take any shift you can take multiple uh
Terry has two I have
two I I have been doing two Gina has two
so you don't have to have one shift um
but just tell us if you want to pray and
you go through the training um where you
would like to be and we'll find a spot
for and that's and and the reason why we
have the shift so we can ensure that
it's 24 hours but of course some people
just commit themselves to saying hey
look I'm fasting on that day for 24
hours so it's covered you know okay so
so praise God whatever the Lord lays on
your heart it it can be a blessing to
someone some too because I have family
members who just don't know the Lord
right and I just feel like the only way
to really penetrate their hearts is
through pray prayer and fasting so just
knowing that people are praying
continuously for like the people that we
love is so encouraging so encouraging
it's what the Bible says I mean some
things are you know these things will
only happen will only happen but through
prayer and fasting amen and you know
some some of these situations people are
are in um maybe not literal prisons I
know something about that but they're in
what's a prison and the Bible says in
Acts chapter 12 when when Peter was in
prison that prayer was offered up
continually for the church by the church
for him and that broke his chain his
chains were was was loosened and so we
do get praise reports of people who have
experienced Deliverance I mean this
demonic stuff is really real
church and and so we've seen and heard
some things that would make the hair
stand up on the back of your necks but
we've also heard how God has delivered
and just brought absolute freedom to
people's lives
amen somebody is saying and we're going
to put the the email back up there too
it says says how can I join how can I
join this
beautiful uh Ministry of the body of
Christ I want to be I want I want to be
trained so we just want to put that
information up there so you can um you
can email the prayer team if you have a
prayer request and you want to be on the
24 that you want to go on the 24-hour
prayer list in one of those categories
or if you are interested in being
trained so you can be a part of this um
the prayer team to to do ministry and
pray for others because I have to say it
truly is uh a blessing to really to to
just be to do intercession to do prayers
of intercession for other people it
really it's a blessing to them and
you're blessed as well you get a
spiritual blessing from that uh that too
I go ahead I could I say this also I
want to shout out Sister Pauline goodan
you know that's my big sister and you
know that's my girl but you know she
does such an amazing job of man managing
the living Mana prayer team email and
she gets all those prayer requests off
and she puts it into prayer uh a prayer
list that we all have and she makes sure
everyone gets I know a copy of the
prayer list that we're praying over all
the time of all the prayer requests that
come in so we could use some people to
help her manage that because there's a
lot going on you know as Ross and Gina
said we have over 400 in the 24hour
prayer fasting Ministry but all the
prayer releas all all together I mean
it's just more than we can count
so yeah so thank God as y'all come and
Ms Charlie you want to join come on join
the ranks of the living man of prayer
yes for sure for sure I go ahead go
ahead Ross just just for for the fun of
giving God the glory when we first
started this Prayer Ministry uh somebody
sent in uh about a child who had been
kidnapped in tah or um Haiti
and he disappeared for like four days
and we started praying for him on the 24
hour and the the prayer team as well and
he was found and recovered and brought
home alive and well within 72 hours of
us amen amen so God does hear these
prayers and he loves people and loves to
help night you and last night you
already mentioned the the problems that
we were having with the studio and and
the the audio and cameras and things not
wanting to work properly and the prayer
team got right on it got right on it it
was such a blessing everything is
working beautifully today so glory to
God praise all glory to God and he uses
our our Tech team
they he just uses to give them ideas on
how to troubleshoot and so we just
praise God I praise God for them the
same way I praise God for your the
prayer team it's just amazing I want to
talk about because this is what
something else that was spoken that was
talked about um during power Wednesday
this last week was prayer journaling and
you guys know if you've heard me mention
I'm very much so into to prayer
journaling and I even brought my current
prayer
Journal my this is my favorite my
favorite book um so much goes on in here
and I have you know several of these uh
throughout the year I'm going to have to
get this huge bookshelf to to store them
but um and you may be wondering okay why
prayer Journal what's the blessing in
that can I just pray and you can just
pray you don't have to journal but I
found that um I had mentioned um that
Janet Paige the conference president's
wife uh several years ago she was our
conference president's wife and she
inspired me to start prayer journaling
and her thing that really what she said
one time when she was speaking is just
about um about Israel like their biggest
sin is they forgot what God had done for
them just when he did so many miracles
and getting them out of Egypt and then
they got into the Wilderness and started
complaining and so that was their
biggest sin is that they forgot about
what God had done and I don't want to
forget and prayer
journaling prayer journaling helps me um
in that area I can I can tell you like
someone said um I can't remember who was
sharing uh about per journaling during
um Power Wednesday but they were
understand you know there's a variety of
ways that you can do that do it there's
no set ways and so I do it in the way
that uh I feel like God has led me to do
it but of course I start with praise and
before I even go into my praise section
like I I had the the the there's a
header of or of on the the prayer
journal and it it always has I always
have a praise that God has something he
did the day before that I can say thank
you God for dot dot dot and so has the
date and then I go into all the other
Praises but there's always like a huge
header at the specific thing that it
starts with so I can go back through the
years going through these prayer
journals and just looking at what God
has done so I don't forget because as we
continue to go through life and we're
praying about things it's easy to get
discouraged when you're in the current
situation and so that you don't forget
and you can remember oh yeah God brought
me out of that to go back and read I
mean one day I just went back and read
read something I I think that journal
was from like 2017 2016 and I said Ivor
look at this look what we were going
through look what the kids were going
through and look what God has done and
so it's very inspiring to to just
remember and it also helps to keep me
organized it helps to keep my prayers
organized because you guys know people
always say oh you know I'm going through
this situation and maybe the prayer team
they're so good at this but you know
regular folk regular folks if somebody
says will you pray for me and you say
yeah I'm gonna pray for you and you
really in you mean to do it when you say
it but then sometimes you forget or it's
just as things are going on you may not
do it um continually um until they get
an answer that can happen and so in the
prayer Journal it helps me because I
have a section of course for I have a
section for myself for my husband for my
family uh but then I have a section for
others and others is a whole category of
just all the prayer requests that I know
other people have and situations going
on and so the prayer journal helps to
keep me organized so I don't forget
about other people's needs and their
problems and so it's just a blessing so
I just want to encourage others who are
inspired by you know the prayer
journaling to just try it try it um my
kids have a kind of a running joke
they're like wow Mommy you're you're I
know this is going in your prayer
Journal I'm like yes this is
going amen they know they know that
that's there's power there's power there
because of God but yes I want you you
guys to just give us some final words
about just what the being involved in
this Prayer Ministry like what what it's
done for you and why you just love to be
a part of it so much I mean I could just
assume why but I want to we want to hear
from
you I think for me just the
encouragement of breakthroughs that have
happened you know Pauline also sends me
a report of Praise reports every week
and so I get to see the other end of the
prayer requests and I get to share them
with with everyone every week and just
knowing that we can intercede for others
is just such a powerful communication
between you and the Lord and seeing what
he's doing is just incredible it's it's
such a gift amen amen well for me
everything about living mana and the
prayer team and this amazing family it's
just a confirmation of the word of God
you know in prison 25 years I had a long
time to learn how to pray and spend time
praying I'm still learning to pray the
Lord's still teaching but he promised me
and I wrote it down tante it's so
amazing that you're talking about prayer
journaling because I wrote down the
vision God gave me that I would be
involved in intercessory prayer but at
the time I wanted to be a worship leader
I was a Church musician and stuff and
and I wanted to you know I wanted to
teach the word and and and God sent me
to Bible school for four years even when
I was there and um yet that thing he
said to me about no you're going to be
In Prayer Ministry you're going to be
involved in this prayer and I come here
and here it is I'm living out the word
that God promised so praise God you're
to give a shout out as well that it is
so humbling and such a gift to be able
to work alongside some of the most
dedicated
heartfelt just absolutely incredible
people of God Amen and they just have
such a heart for prayer and a heart for
others and it's just been this community
that is so strong like we are just it's
it's been an incredible and let's not
take it for granted you see us here on
the camera and sometimes you see prayer
Warrior leadership coming and leading
out in prayer but if you look right
there in that chat there are prayer
Warriers right in front of us right
there's Sister Pauline there's brother
gr brother gr out of the hospital right
back on post praying yes brother good to
see you Diana Johnson's right there in
the chat sister lynnette's always right
there sister Jack I mean just on fire
and and and today we want to send a
special shout out to Sister Sister
Angela y'all know what happens once I
start calling these names right I'm
gonna sit here and call all 50 of
them prayer war is on fire Young Brother
Enoch we love you he's our he's the baby
of the bunch the youngest one brother
Kirk brother I mean just on and on
brother PJ all the living man of Prayer
Warriors we love y'all every one of you
brother Elco you know what happen see I
can't stop so oh G was reminding us that
they prayed and fasted for us to get
this house oh that was a miracle that
was was a miracle there were 80
applicants for this house and so it's
kind of just a blessing to be able to
share our living room with you every
week because if it wasn't for you and
the Lord we would not be sitting here
today and listen I don't want I don't
want to keep going but I will say this
look 88 88 applicants right
and you know my background one of them
was the top five one of the top five
applicants was a police yes he was he
was a community police officer what are
the chances of that y military for for
them to CH to choose a because you were
still on parole then right you were he
just got I was still on I just got
parole oh that's right you just got off
to choose
anever yes over a police officer yeah
wow that God that
God that was God glory yeah yes he
amazing to me prayer is Jesus did it for
us in John 13:14 1516 and
17 he prayed for himself he prayed for
the disciples and then he says blessed
are those who will hear of me through
your
testimony and we are that we are that
group of reading the scriptures and
hearing Jesus reading Jesus's prayer
hearing the Holy Spirit there's no
better place to be than in the footsteps
of Christ it's the only safe place to be
amen and it's and and the prayer team is
a family amen they we're we're so close
uh to each other we speak to each other
every day it's not just a weekend uh
thing
um and it's it's amazing uh to be a part
of this uh and it is
service
amen amen you know the prayer team used
to yes you said they meet every day oh
used to meet
okay we have mid
afternoon tightness amongst us by
meeting every day and I was thinking wow
this prayer team is something else here
yeah they the
dedication um I I mean we just the
dedication of all of our volunteers here
at Living M church is amazing they
definitely buy into the mission of what
God has called us to do I say this every
week that my husband could not do this
by himself he and I could not do this by
ourselves we need all of our loving uh
volunteers from our Tech Team to our
prayer team to our board members to
everyone who supports uh living man a
church with their time and their talent
we need all of you speaking of that um
there's going to be an email going out
to the excuse me to the church members
here very soon um asking about how you
would like to get involved in the church
and you're going to be providing us with
your uh spiritual gifts and talents and
and things like that that you've you've
already been a part of and that you just
feel like you could be a blessing and so
we're just going to see how we can get
more of you involved uh to join and be
more of an active part of this church
because truly this community that God
has formed uh between the prayer team
and uh the tech team and and just
everyone again Who's involved it truly
is a blessing and it helps us to be able
to reach the world and so the commitment
that I see in the prayer team on um how
they're just always so available it
doesn't matter if it's night or the or
day or in the middle of the night
someone's going to to wake up or maybe
already be up and say okay we're on it
we're praying for you uh and so it's
just such it's truly truly uh such a
blessing and we just want to say a thank
you to to Terry and to Amar and to Gina
and to Ross and to the whole prayer team
and for those who dedicate and give
their time uh to this ministry so we
want to to go out with prayer speaking
before we go out with prayer I just want
to encourage everyone to make sure that
you stay tuned for the sermon because
Pastor Meer sermon today is about prayer
and it is a powerful one you're not
going to want to miss it invite your
friends invite your family invite
whoever your co-workers anyone put it on
your social media invite them to church
today because they truly will be blessed
by this message and so so I'm going to
ask uh let's ask I'm going to ask sister
Amar to close us out in prayer amen sure
amen Lord Jesus we just want to thank
you today for your Sabbath we want to
thank you for this time um during
Sabbath school just
to really lift up um
Evangelistic weekend and the prayer team
Lord and how we can all be involved in
prayer all the time we are just inviting
living Mana members anyone who is
listening lord it's just an honor to be
able to communicate with you directly
and intercede for others who may not be
able to Lord so we just thank you for
this time we lift up Pastor ior for his
upcoming sermon and we just um thank you
in advance Lord for everything that
you're doing in our lives and just
blessing us daily in Jesus precious name
we pray amen amen amen amen
yes thank you all and please stay tuned
as we continue to Fellowship here at
Living Mana Church uh we're entering
into our divine worship time so please
stay tuned uh and invite a friend to
church God bless
[Music]
you
in the great North Atlantic Ocean
there's a British Island Paradise that
is like heaven on Earth it's known for
its beautiful pink sand beaches rugged
rock formations and captivatingly clear
turquoise Waters everything everything
is easy on the eyes relaxing to the
senses and calming to the nerves with a
land mass of just 20 square mil and a
population of only 65,000 it's a small
piece of paradise enjoyed by relative
few but did you know that this piece of
heaven on Earth was once called the
aisle of devils sounds crazy doesn't it
in fact during the 1500s this island was
on nobody's bucket list the screeching
of cahs the squealing of swine the
whistling of the tree frogs and the
howling of the wind sounded like the
Wailing of demons to superstitious saors
many believed that this island was
haunted by evil spirits but nothing
could be further from the
truth history tells us that Bermuda was
named after the 16th century Spanish
Navigator W Bermudas he was the first to
accidentally discover this uninhabited
Paradise in
1505 though it was first discovered by a
Spaniard bermo was never claimed or
colonized by the Spanish some of the
local tur guys told me that the reason
why the Spanish never claimed this
island was because of fear fear of the
treacherous refilled Waters and the
imaginary evil spirits that supposedly
haunted this island jokingly some say
that bermudes lived up to his name he
came for one day and then he left that's
why they call him W bermudes it's a
humorous say but I can imagine very
unsettling for Spain thinking about the
possibilities that could have
been it wasn't until over a century
later that the island was finally
settled by the English in 16 12 so
although named after a Spaniard English
is the mother tongue of this British
colony now I find it interesting that
the a of devils happens to be one of the
most beautiful and harmless places on
Earth there are no danger snakes or
poisonous spiders or Ferocious Beast
that can harm you in fact seldom will
you even see a shark in the water if you
ask me this place is harmless very
habitable this is God's country a
desired destination for multitudes who
are looking for rest and relaxation from
all over the
world now I found it very foolish that a
country missed out on colonizing this
uninhabited Paradise why because of fear
you know as I thought about that I began
to realize that many people are doing
the exact same foolish thing today you
see friends there is a true Paradise
that God is preparing for us in heaven a
sweet harmless Haven of Rest a place
with no tears or fears a place where
there's no dying nor sorrow nor crying
or pain a perfect Paradise where the
flowers Never Fade laughter never ceases
Joy never dims people never die children
don't get sick and the sky never darkens
it's a place that you surely don't want
to miss but tragically when we all get
to heaven and the road is caught be
under many people will be absent why
well for the same reason why Bermuda is
missed out on Bermuda one word fear
you see many people in our world are
afraid to trust God with their lives
afraid to let him have full control
afraid of surrender and
self-sacrifice many people think that
God is some kind of tyrant some kind of
celestial Sheriff that is out there to
get them and make them miserable and
Holiness but the Bible says that God has
not given us the spirit of fear but
Power love and a sound mind fear is not
of God friends it is the enemy's work to
make us afraid but God is the one who
said to ISA
fear not for I have redeemed thee I've
called thee by name you are mine he's
the same one that said to Joshua have
not I commanded thee be strong and of a
good courage do not be afraid nor be
dismayed for the Lord your God is with
you wherever you go and he is the same
one that says to all of us today let not
your heart be troubled you believe in
God believe also in me in my father's
house are many mansions if it were not
so I would have told you
I go to prepare a place for you and if I
go and prepare a place for you I will
come again to receive you into myself
that where I am there you may be also
fear is not from God fear is from the
enemy of God and fear is an acronym it
stands for false evidence appearing real
just like w day Bermudez many people are
being deceived and duped by the devil's
false evidence and because of that many
will miss out on the Celestial
Paradise my friend allow me to speak to
your heart today is there something that
the devil has caused you to believe that
makes you afraid to trust God is there a
demonic distraction that has deterred
you from the path to
Paradise or maybe there's a decision
that you need to make but you hesitate
because you're afraid of failure well
today I want to encourage you do not be
deceived by the devil's delusions nor be
deterred by his demonic distraction
ractions let God remove all the
unfounded fear from your heart and let
him replace it with his perfect peace
and his Saving Grace I invite you to go
forward in holy boldness and unwavering
Faith go and claim the Heavenly Paradise
as your own and don't allow the fear to
get in the way now the way to overcome
fear is to be filled with love you see
fear will cast you out of paradise the
Bible says that God's perfect love will
cast out fear from you so instead of
focusing on the uncertainty of your
circumstance instead of dwelling upon
the difficulties and musing upon all the
mistakes you've made in life take your
eyes off of yourself and place them on
the Blessed Christ let him pour out his
love in your heart and just as darkness
is dispelled by light as God's love
comes in the devil's fears will go out
and instead of being driven by fear
false evidence appearing real you will
be drawn by faith Faith which is the
substance of things hoped for and the
evidence of Things Not Seen faith that
will lead us all the way into the
Heavenly Paradise not just for one day
but for all eternity and by God's grace
I'll see you
[Music]
there we hope you've been blessed and
inspired by this new reflections of Hope
episode this episode is one of many
that's been produced all over the world
if you haven't done so yet please give
our video a like share it with your
friends and please follow us on
Instagram Facebook and YouTube if you'd
like to see more inspiring episodes and
get access to much more uplifting
content please go now to
patreon.com revelation of Hope and sign
up to be a member of our patreon page
your monthly support will not only give
you early access to many more inspiring
videos but will also enable us to
continue to produce more of these
cinematic object lessons from nature our
goal is to produce and release these
episodes much more frequently so please
prayerfully consider partnering with us
so that we may continue to share the
hope of Jesus all over the world thank
you so much for your support Aloha and
[Music]
Marin
welcome to SDA BNB rooms rides Sabbath
meals and more by Adventist host
worldwide traveling somewhere soon and
plan to spend hundreds of dollars on an
Airbnb or hotel stay at a fellow 7th Day
Adventist Church members house for free
and make a new friend using SDA BNB
visiting a new location and have nowhere
to go for lunch after church on Sabbath
find a local SDA host who would love to
have you over for lunch when you're in
the area sdmb is free to sign up and
free to put a listing up we have
advanage hosts from around the world
that are willing to help with rooms
rides Sabbath meals and more SDA
businesses churches and Ministries also
have their listings on sdnb so you know
what's going on when you are visiting a
new place start by putting your own SDA
BNB listing up where you live do you
have an extra room in your house or you
willing to give rides to church or to
the airport or willing to host someone
for Sabbath lunch at your place do you
have an SDA business like a restaurant
or dental office or an active church or
Ministry share your hospitable listings
on sdnb now with fellow Adventists who
travel to your area to join your
Adventist brothers and sisters worldwide
in sharing our Hospitality with each
other it only takes a minute sign up now
become a host for free at sdnb
[Music]
.org
[Applause]
[Music]
welcome back living Mana church family
we are so happy that you have chosen to
stay with us uh for church today and if
you are just joining for the US for the
first time please put in the chat where
you are viewing from we want to say a
special welcome to you and if this is
your first time we want to say an even
more special welcome to you because this
is your very first time worshiping with
living Mana online church today and we
just want to know what what what your
name is where you're visiting from and
we'd love to just say welcome to you so
please put that in the chat now while
you some of you are doing that please
you can also put your prayer requests
because our prayer team is waiting to
collect your prayer request brother
Terry's gonna pray over as many as
requests as he possibly can um when he
is when he's on to do the prayer time so
and those that the prayer request that
he doesn't get to the prayer time that
prayer time the prayer team does collect
all of your prayer requests and they
pray over all of them so please put in
the chat your prayer requests and put in
the chat where you are viewing from we
have uh Long Island New York welcome
Happy Sabbath to you we have Justin from
Northern Ontario welcome we have Brazil
um beautiful country of Brazil lucinta
from Brazil hope I said your name right
happy Sabbath to you welcome to living
Mana church we have Linda from Ohio and
again if this is your first time if
anybody's viewing for the first time
please put a one in the chat because we
want to say welcome to you as well um I
forgot during the first program to talk
about my my my my shirt as many of you
can see it says I can do all things
through Christ which strengthens me and
you know that's one of the one of the
most popular uh text from the Bible that
people quote but I can say it really hit
me when we were in
Israel and we were able to visit a place
where Paul was in prison and they say
that's where he uh that's where they say
that experience is where this text came
from and so now when I quote this now
when I quote this I'm thinking of the
author which was Paul and what he was
going through and I have a totally
different perspective and when I quote
this and um because that's that's who he
held on to he held on to God in that
type of situation and then I compareed
what I'm going through to you know being
in prison for my faith I'm not going
through something as bad as that and so
if Paul could hold on and and just ask
for strength from God and hold on I can
do it also so it encourages me uh when
I'm going through things as well so I'm
hoping that this will encourage you to
every time you are faced with an
obstacle that you um and you feel like
you're not strong up you can say you
know um I you can claim this promise
that you can do all things through
Christ because he strengthens you and so
that is our that is our t-shirt quote
from the Bible today so hopefully that
is a blessing to all of you thank you
for putting in the chat where you guys
are viewing from so again welcome and we
are just so thankful that we have so
many viewing from from all um around the
world is such a blessing and speaking of
that we're so blessed because we do have
some first readings of uh um people
potential members that want to become
members of living Mana church and this
is the first reading so I want to to
read those right now and then next week
we are going to to do the second uh the
second reading so the first uh reading
um is for shelden Cooper and this is
from the first bilingual 7th Day
Adventist Church
and this is for Sheldon Cooper so we are
looking forward to having Sheldon
Sheldon Cooper become a member of the
living Mana church and we'll do that
second reading next week so we're just
looking forward to uh the message that
God has for us today I I we've already
mentioned that it's going to be Pastor
Meer sermon is about prayer and we heard
so much about what the prayer team does
here at Living Mana church and it's such
a blessing and the power of Prayer so it
is our prayer that from the the hearing
about what the prayer team has done and
just different ways that you can pray
and that from today's message that you
will be inspired to just really uh get
into prayer and just and just allow God
to have you have such a powerful prayer
life and communication time with him uh
that that will be your desire after
leave leaving living Mana church today
we also want to talk about um our
Outreach Sabbath which spent a portion
of the Sabbath School uh today talking
about that that's November 18th and that
is going to be um a Sabbath where Living
manag Church online church we will not
be here in studio we will not be online
at all that day and why again you may
ask because we are going to be out in
the community we are going we're asking
all of our members and viewership those
who have been so blessed by living Mana
church and you um you've been so blessed
and you've learned so much and you want
to just go out and do service and do
Outreach to reach other people and to
help other people with their practical
uh needs you will be able we want you to
do that all the time as God puts it on
your heart but this sabbath we are
shutting Church down so we can go out
into um our respective communities and
be a blessing to others and so if you
want to to be able you can do that um
and you can come up with your the your
own way on how you're going to do that
but if you would like to uh purchase a a
t-shirt or a hoodie that has living Mana
Church on it and it has Outreach on the
back you can choose Outreach or you can
you can get it uh personalized the way
you would like to have it there's
different colors we are going to
hopefully be going out and be uniformed
as we are going out into all of the
world because our viewership and
membership is all around the world and
so we are going to be doing service in
all of the world living Mana Church the
members are doing the service and the
ministry and you will be able to uh you
can if you choose to have a t-shirt or a
hoodie that has living manage Church on
it the way that you can do that is you
can scan the QR code you can see that in
the corner of your screen scan your QR
code and I believe that it also the link
also went in the chat so you can do it
that way too if you can't scan the QR
code or if you have like no idea what
that is some people just not familiar
with that so you can the link is in the
chat um as well the other uh way that we
have sent this out and that is through
communication through our texting app if
you have not signed up for the texting
app and you'd like to get the link that
way or just stay connected with living
Mana Church all throughout the week so
you can hear what's going on be reminded
of when programs are coming on or going
live so you don't forget we just want to
remind you on how you can sign up to be
a part of our our our
chat um system from um living Mana
church you can text LM O2
84576 and you will get you will be
connected in real time with our text
from our communication team from living
Mana church and so that link that's in
the chat if you're having a hard time
getting that you cannot scan the QR code
you will get we're going to send out
this link one more time so that you will
have an opportunity to order these
t-shirts we are you know in some places
it's already not Sabbath anymore so you
can go ahead and do that in some places
it's still Sabbath so you can um I want
to wait until after Sabbath to order
your your your T-shirt but I would say
please order before or by or by Monday
so that gives you time to get your
t-shirt before November 18th and before
we do the Outreach and so we're really
looking forward uh to what God is going
to do during this time and the blessing
it's going to be to so many of you and
to all of us who get to experience some
Outreach to do on that day on on
November uh the 18th so we also like to
just share with you if you um want to
talk with Pastor Meyers he does have
Virtual Office hours we want to remind
you on how you can do that as well you
will be able to send an email to Patrice
Liv mana. live and you can set up
Virtual Office hours that way if you
feel like you need to talk to him um if
you want to to be able to talk to him um
and set up a set up a meeting you this
is the way that you can do that is to
set up some a virtual office hours and
we also we
mentioned um we mentioned in the last um
program how you can get you if you have
a prayer request that you haven't
presented if you haven't presented um
here on living Manana Church platform
but you would and it's in the middle of
the week and you'd like to get the
prayer team the the prayer request so
that they can pray for you we just want
to let you know how you can do that
where you can email your prayer request
and the prayer team will pray for you um
and that's prayer Liv mana. live prayer
Liv mana. live and that's how you can
get your prayer request when you if you
heard you were in our first program and
you want to get a prayer request to them
about the
24hour uh when they're praying for
prayer request the 24-hour prayer
request time you definitely can use that
same email to be able uh to do that as
well and so our prayer team is ready and
willing I can't wait to get your prayer
requests because they are so passionate
about what they do and we praise God for
them we praise God for you and for all
that you do for being a part of living
Mana Church tuning in each and every
week telling people about living Mana
Church sharing with living Mana Church
on your uh platform on your your virtual
uh platform we're just so thankful to
all of you thank you thank you thank you
continue to share let them know that we
are a virtual Church we're an online
church and we are a church that cares
about their practical needs so please
share what we do here at Living Mana
Church um and you know tell them the why
what a blessing you get from coming here
the reason why you keep coming back each
and every week so let them know that we
care about their mental health we have
mental health programs every Monday this
Monday will be off but we'll be back the
following Monday so we have mental
health Mondays we care about their
physical health share um one of the the
clips from True Health Tuesday so that
they can hear what our doctors are are
sharing let them know that we believe in
the power of prayer and that uh what our
prayer team does and you can even let
them know that they can join us for our
power Wednesdays or they can send in a
prayer request um just let them know
that we'll pray for them if they are in
need of prayer or they can just come and
listen and be blessed and we even care
about their financial needs let them
know um that uh we have programming on
uh their fi Financial areas and yes
that's every Thursday just to let just
remind you and whoever you may be
sharing this with that we have money
answers all thing with Don Daniels and
that has been such a blessing I know
many of you have been blessed um the
program is getting a lot of views and a
lot of you guys are there live to ask
your questions and so it truly has been
a blessing so let them know that this is
Church online and yes we're doing church
out of the box but we also uh we're so
out of the box that we just trying to
meet all of their practical needs as we
can as God allows and leads us to do and
so when you're sharing about living Mana
Church please share these different
topics that we cover because these are
the things that people are talking about
each and every day they're talking about
their own mental health their children's
mental health or their health their
family's health their need of prayer
finances how can we all want to grow and
do better with our finances and so we
preach the word of God here Pastor Myers
is very committed and tries to preach
the word of God responsibly as God leads
him and so there's so many things going
on here at Living Mana church so these
are all the things that you can can
share with your friends your family and
just those who you want to get the
gospel gospel to and it's so easy to
just share a link that's all you have to
do push a button click or a click you
can just do that it's so very very easy
so we ask that you continue to do that
and we just want to thank you for all
the other blessings for praying for
living Mana church and for those who
have financially been giving uh to
living Mana church we want to say thank
you this is how we're able to to do this
we're able to get equipment and all the
things that we need to be live each and
every week all throughout the week and
we're able to advertise and let people
people know that we're here in that way
virtually as well and so by your giving
you help us to be able to do that we
also have a benevolence fund um that
when people are in need and they ask for
some some need they're in need and
they're asking for assistance from the
church we're able to help um some
through the benevolence fund and because
you are so faithful in your giving we
are able to do that so we just want to
uh thank you for giving and um for those
who want to continue to give or start to
give we just want to tell you how you
can do that at this time so one of the
easiest ways that a lot of people like
to do is through cash app because it's
right there on your phone it's just a
couple of clicks and it's all done and
so our our handle is living Mana church
and you can um you can give your tithe
and we are part of the northeastern
conference so your tithe goes to the
northeastern conference and it supports
the whole worldwide 7-Day Adventist
Church and then your local church budget
or the local budget stays right here
with living Mana church and that's where
we pay for the advertising and for the
maintenance for all the things that we
do for the cameras the monitors
everything we do to be online that comes
out of the the local church budget
another way to be able to give is to go
to adventistgiving.org and you can go to
living Mana online church and there you
have a virtual tith envelope and you can
again put your tith which goes to the
northeastern conference the local church
budget that stays with living Mana
Church the benevolence fund is there
there's so many different categories
that you will see on that TI envelope so
it can go wherever you would like it uh
to go and then the Third Way is you can
write a check to living Mana church and
you can mail it in to living Mana church
and our address is PO Box Owens
Crossroads and that's Alabama
35763 and you will be able to mail that
in to living Mana church and just say
what is for tithe what is for offering
and what other areas you may want to
give to and you can do the same thing
with the cash app you can put uh there's
a section where you can put exactly uh
where you want uh These funds to go and
how much is for For What and so we just
want to again thank you for supporting
the church through your prayers through
your financial gifts it is such a
blessing to be able to be here um and to
see this church grow from just from the
ground up it has just been a true
blessing to see God's Mission and his
dream that he put um in our hearts that
is is his mission but he put it in our
hearts to do this and just to see it
work each and every week and how it's
growing and how it's touching people's
lives and you are a part of that because
you're here you worship with us and
because of your giving you are a part of
that as well and we just want to say
thank you we want to thank God at this
time and just thank him for all of his
many blessings that he gives to all of
us and if you would just please bow your
heads with me as we
pray Heavenly Father Lord I just thank
you so much for just your Miracles and
your power and how you work things out
Lord you um I I prayed this during power
Wednesday and I'm praying it here again
Lord help us to choose to trust before
we are choosing anxiety and worry and
Lord you in the last 24 hours you have
proven so much to me that I just always
need to go in that trust realm and just
trust you with everything even when
everything looks chaotic or not going to
work you are in control and it makes
more sense to trust you than to worry
and to have anxiety so Lord I I just I
thank you and I and I praise you uh for
for giving me that life lesson today
Lord and I just want to thank you for
all the faith F members and viewing
audience that we have here at Living
Mana church I am thankful we are
thankful and how they share um on their
social media about living Mana Church
how they share with their friends and
their family and their co-workers and
just people about living Mana Church
Lord I just pray that you will continue
to empower them to do that um so they
are our they are our virtual and real
Bible workers too Lord they just share
about the the things that we're teaching
here or maybe some of the things that
they're learning that would be a
blessing to other people and I just ask
that you will bless them as they
continue to do that Lord I pray for
those who will be participating in the
November 18th Outreach Sabbath here for
living Mana church I pray for the ideas
that they are coming up with that you
will bless their experience um and that
it will be a blessing to those who they
serve Lord and I just just pray that you
will continue to guide them in that
direction Lord this world is in such a
mess I know it's always been in a mess
since sin entered in but Lord it is such
a mess right now there's so much hurt so
much pain there's war and innocent
people being killed and and and on both
sides of the situation Lord it has been
a very it's just such a sad thing and
it's so sad for us to just watch day in
and day out Lord we just want you to
come as quickly as possible to take us
away from all of this but we know
there's things that we have to do before
you come help us to be faithful in the
mission that you've given to us help us
not to be afraid to share the gospel
with others help this gospel to truly go
into all of the world Lord so that you
can come so that you can come and
deliver your children from this wicked
wicked world that is just so painful to
be a part of Lord and right now is one
of those times where it's just so hard
to even turn on on the news to watch all
the things that are going on and Lord we
just
pray that um again that you will just
give us strength to open our mouths just
to open our mouths to just share the
gospel and not to be afraid Lord but to
share in the way that you want us to
share Lord and help our experience of
helping others being doing service on
November 18th let that be an opening
door of us building connections and
friendships with people
um that are in need and that we're
helping and that they will want to know
more about this God that we serve or
more about this truth that we teach from
the Bible and even more about living
Mana Church Lord as we continue to try
to be a witness and guide them and
connect them to you God Lord this is our
prayer I pray for the message that
Pastor Myers is going to preach today
that it will touch hearts in such a
special way that we will leave here
being on fire for the power of prayer
and all and the way that you allow us to
connect to you in such a powerful way
and what you can do through prayer Lord
we pray all these many blessings and we
pray these things in your Jesus in your
name
[Music]
amen
e
amen greetings Saints of the most high
God welcome to another living Mana
intercessory prayer time here with my
lovely bride amra this is indeed the day
the Lord ha made we will rejoice and be
glad in it so glad to be here with you
again Saints to serve the Lord and to
serve you his people want to do just a
few shout outs want to send a shout out
to sister jod mlar I belov sister jod
jod we love you uh as she's mourning her
mother has entered into her rest uh just
yesterday evening and so we thank God
for you and thank God for the love that
you showed her sister jod be encouraged
you and your entire family also want to
send a shout out to Sister Angela who's
not feeling well we love you sister
Angela you were going to be here with us
today to lead an intercessory prayer but
uh we'll we'll hold your spot so come on
sister Patty G welcome back good to see
you in the chat there Lord bless you and
Brother Juan we love y'all Sister Lisa
Clark I see you there greetings sister
Candace always sending out greetings we
miss you too love you too sis amen
sister Pauline I see you in the chat and
Jay Jay I saw your prayer request and
then you put the lyrics to a song Now
Behold the Lamb the precious lamb of God
that is a beautiful song Jay and and it
kind of goes hand in hand with your
prayer request you want to know your
place in the body of Christ and for your
life there was a lyric in that song says
I didn't always do right you told me to
go left I went right but now I'm
standing right here in the midst of my
tears proclaiming you to be the Lamb of
God so definitely stand on that brother
that's a that's a powerful song there
and then I want to send a shout out to
Sister Patrice and brother Fred and
brother Gavin holding it down behind the
scenes our amazing Tech Team and our
producer just love y'all and thank you
for the amazing work that you do um you
know Saints
um when we were watching the uh video
from Taj uh sister Candace put in the
chat that she loved that little acronym
fear false evidence appearing real you
know the Bible says that Satan is the
God of this world he's the prince of the
power of the air 1 John chapter 5 tells
us that the whole world this world we
live in is under the influence of
wickedness and we are here but you know
prayer is such an awesome gift it allows
us to to rise above the realities of
this world the false evidence in this
world that appears re real you know the
devil's a liar he has no power but in
the lie but the LIE has no power over US
unless we believe it but when we're
always dwelling down here in this
tainted atmosphere those things have a
powerful influence on us prayer is God's
way of allowing us to escape to rise
above that in the Holy Ghost and so we
want to encourage you to pray continue
to pray don't give up don't give in no
matter what it looks like rise above
that false evidence appearing real rise
above that fear in jesus' name we want
to pray and thank God for you today as
you continue to pray and as we listen to
some of the praise reports here's
evidence right here that God is hearing
and answering prayer God is the greatest
reality amen amen I have so many amazing
praise reports that I'm gonna have to
read some of them next week so if I
didn't get to yours it's coming I'm just
so blown away by some of these amazing
ways that God is working in your lives
amen the first one comes from Hattie m
thank you dear Lord for improving
Connie's Health to the stage that she is
off life support amen I pray for her
continued Improvement in the name of
Jesus name amen praise God um Jerry
Harvey Leonard now she submitted one
last night that I will be reading next
week but she also has a small praise
well this is not small her student loan
was deferred until February so that was
a huge praise report for her and I will
be sharing another one that she shared
last night with us was great great one
for next week Teresa Hatton shared that
she asked us to pray for her son and for
Terry to reach out and to write to him
in prison and Look What the Lord Has
Done oh amen hi brother Terry God is so
good my son is being processed to be
released praise the Lord once I have the
rest of the information I will be sure
to reach out to you thank you and the
prayer warriors of living Mana but I
give God all the praise and glory in
jesus' name amen amen amen from matina
Hamilton requesting prayer for housing
for my grandson in Montana God answered
our prayers for my grandson found he
found a place and his rent and de
deposits have been paid Amazing Grace
thank you all for your
interceding praise reports for both of
my sisters who are coming along quite
well and in good spirits thank you for
your prayers amen from Regina B praise
report God showed himself in a way only
he could I thought I'd have to fight to
justify myself at work for my one-year
evaluation so that I can get an
adjustment this gave me so much anxiety
but I didn't think to pray about money I
thought it was my fight God showed me
it's his power and he is things working
in my favor behind the scenes turns out
all the managers up to my Chief
Financial Officer all fought for me to
get a raise that was above my
expectations I was on vacation and my
first day back I got the news and all I
could do was thank God because student
loans just restarted amen then a few
weeks later which was last week I said
out loud how I just needed an influx of
money to help with the holidays well
today God showed me his hand and Grace
again we got an email that we will be
giving another rise in retro praise God
and then I have just one more from
Jackie
Carr hello prayer war warriors
especially brother Terry I have been
following living Mana online Church from
close to the beginning but last year in
October we found out that my little
brother Joe had Thro cancer by the time
he actually got into a cancer doctor and
threw all the testing the lump on his
neck had doubled we were terrified
because this is how we lost our dad my
brother Joe has been a single dad for
many years and he was so scared as how
to take care of his finances and Kids
when the doctors told him he couldn't
work due to the aggressiveness of the
treatment he was going to go through I
was watching living Mana online church
and saw the requests and thought it
could help I put it in and when brother
Terry read my request I was ugly crying
just to feel that living Mana online
church and the prayer warriors cared
enough to read it
makes me tear up still his work had an
auction right afterwards and they raised
$54,000 to help him through and I know
God had a hand in that it still makes me
cry for how grateful I am anyways he is
now cancer free praise God for three
months and I mostly thank God but also
for all the prayers that help my brother
heal thank you so much for all you do
man somebody give God glory glory honor
and praise amen and I mean these These
are amazing prayers and prayer requests
that God's answering and God is you know
Miracles are nothing for God there's
nothing too hard for our God and so we
want to continue to ask you to continue
to pray trusting and believing listen no
matter what you've gone through you're
not what you've gone through you're not
what you've come through you're not what
you've done you're not what has been
done to you you are what God says you
are and you're all that he says you are
you can do all that he says you can do
because he has paid the price with the
Precious Blood of our Lord Jesus Christ
and so Saints be encouraged and stand
strong in the Lord and in the power of
His might and so listen you know I I
just want to ask you to join us and as
we go to the throne of grace and
speaking of prayer one of the one of the
prayers our Lord prayed in John chapter
17 was that we would be one in him as he
is in the father and they are in us that
we are one this happens because we are
together one the body of Christ no big
eyes no little use we're all together
one we're stronger together you know one
man said something one time that really
impressed me he said there are a lot of
things greater than me there not a whole
lot of things greater than we and so
let's stick together Saints and and and
and Endeavor to keep the unity of the
spirit in the bond of peace and so
father as we come to the throne of grace
today remembering the word you taught us
in the in the prayer you taught us and
how to pray the first word out of your
mouth was our thank you God that we are
not alone thank thank you that we are
family thank you that you you you you
you sent your son Jesus Christ to this
world Lord God to purchase us to save us
to deliver us to heal us God we thank
you because we know that we're not
deserving there is nothing that we could
ever do to earn your love and to earn
your grace and to earn your mercy and to
earn your goodness you are love you are
God our creator and we thank you today
we praise you we bless you we lift you
up and magnify you help us to remember
by your spirit all the good things
you've done for us all the way you've
brought us how many times have we looked
through our prayer journal and looked
back and declared had it not been for
the Lord that was on my side I certainly
would have perished in that mess I would
have perished in that storm never could
have made it without you Jesus and so we
thank you for your goodness Lord forgive
us oh God when we're forgetting forgive
us oh Lord when we become such leaky
vessels Lord God when you speak to us
and bless us today and tomorrow we done
forgot it already there word says
oppression maketh A A wise man mad but
Lord I pray in the name of Jesus in the
midst of our storms let us not forget
your goodness let us not forget your
grace and let us not forget how you've
been so long suffering with us and
patient with us in Jesus name and so
Lord as we come with these prayer
requests which are many we know you're
not overwhelmed by them we know none of
this catches You by surprise your word
says thy will be done in earth as it is
in heaven and so Heavenly Father we pray
that you provide provide for the lives
of these Saints and these precious ones
that have come to you Lord God in faith
today thank you for Sister Janet Abbot
Abby who visited us today Lord God in
his heading up Outreach Lord we cover
her with prayer today we pray encamp
your angels around her her home her
family her children who are away
studying in school her husband father
God be with him Lord God our precious
Elder be with him and bless him and keep
him in Jesus glorious name and bless
that Ministry Lord that it would go
forth oh Lord God and bring forth glory
and honor and praise unto you Lord in
Jesus name and we thank you also for
healing in Sister Angela's life today
Lord in Jesus name God bless and heal
touch save and deliver brother Gerald
best is reminding us to pray for healing
for Randy in DC Lord God and Lord I want
to pray for this Gardener who's out here
today I I this has never happened but
thank you Lord he needs some prayer
Francisco needs prayer today Lord for
being here at just at this time exactly
and so so Lord we thank you for storms
and for trials I thank you for brother
Elco we prayed for him last week when he
had a a going through a trial a couple
weeks ago and then today we couldn't
help but notice there was an extra pep
in his step an extra boost in his Spirit
something Lively about him Lord you
bring us through those storms that we
can know you as our deliverer you bring
us through those storms Lord God because
you using those storms to destroy
something some doubt some unbelief some
whatever it is in us that's blocking us
from seeing you clearly as we ought to
see you because you're good God you're
merciful and kind and you're real and so
we thank you today in Jesus name and
Vanessa
Grace uh uh we're praying for her she's
asking us to pray for those fires in
Hawaii we want to remember that today in
Jesus name praying for sister jod and
her family they would find healing and
comfort in the middle of their trials
Lord I pray that you speak to the body
of Christ at Living Mana that we would
all understand Lord that our greatest
ability is our availability and that we
would make ourselves available unto you
oh Lord and you will show us amazing
ways that we could be used and I pray
for that one Lord God who would look at
a a service for you and think it's
insignificant we don't have to be under
the lights we ain't got to be out where
everybody can see us Lord we can do
amazing works for you that no one knows
about but just you us and whoever it is
we're doing it for Lord I pray that we
know that whatever we do for Christ only
that really is going to last in Jesus
name sister Leela Peterson Lord God is
reminding us to pray for our brother and
her husband Wes who traveling for work
Grant him traveling mercies as you have
been so faithful to do Lord we lift up
our brother Trevor Lord God his mom and
his sister and Trevor's knees Lord we're
praying that you bring him healing I
even saw my sister said can I get in on
that knees prayer and so we're praying
for her knees too Lord God as a matter
of fact Lord we praying for all our
needs that we spend more time on them
God in Jesus name seeking your face God
and for those whose needs are bothering
them Lord grant them comfort and healing
in Jesus name Brother David Hernandez is
praying for Valentine Hernandez Lord God
who's been diagnosed with cancer help
and heal save touch and deliver as we
know you can by his stripes we are
healed and we're standing on those
promises today in Jesus name epsi
reviewed is praying for a husband who
has left the church Heavenly Father
anyone who feels the need to leave Lord
God lord I know and many of us know
where where we gonna go to where will we
go God but it is you who have the words
of life let us not be allured and I by
Satan's allurements Lord God by his
false advertisements things that never
will satisfy things that will never will
fulfill us things that will never answer
life's questions things that will never
be the solution to our deeper and
innermost needs Lord God I pray for
anyone that's feeling tempted to go away
and to go astray Lord God help them to
see that it's only a lie that the enemy
is using to pull them the way Devil's
apples always got a worm in it Lord God
sin Thrills but it always kills and so I
just pray pray in Jesus name father keep
your people today Lord God in Jesus
glorious name no matter how bad it might
look let them stay on this ship of Zion
heavenly father in Jesus name though it
appear to crash against the Rocks Lord
this is our salvation and we thank you
for providing it for us in Jesus name
and sister ggs ask us to pray for the
elderly who need someone to pray in
Spanish father God we still got the gift
of tongues manifested in the right way
here and we know you will send someone
to speak that lovely Ro IC language of
Spanish in the language that she needs
to hear the language of Heaven in Jesus
name father we thank you for Christina
Bourne that she who's overcoming coid
bless heel touch save and deliver in her
life today Sister Charlotte who is
watching from her hospital bed today
Lord she's responding to her medication
be with her and keep her Lord sister
Nicole is reminding us that we prayed
for her friend Sonia to find a job and
she's got an interview coming up Monday
thank you for hearing and answering
prayer sister Freda Serrano Lord God is
praying for her grandsons Alex and Mike
who are incarcerated Lord I've seen
firsthand What a Mighty work you can do
in the prisons so be there Lord Jesus
with them speak to their hearts and
Minds right now we pray God and bring
them out of Darkness Lord Alicia
Northington is praying for Dale Lewis
who's addicted to drugs father God I
thank you that you created us all that
we will worship something we will be
addicted to something God May that thing
that we find that we addicted to be you
and the ministry oh Lord God of your
kingdom in Jesus name and so bring this
brother out of his addictions Lord
father God help him oh Lord we pray to
find that one thing that is the joy of
his soul that thing that will feel the
Deep void in his life Lord we know
that's only you who are big enough to do
that we continue to lift up dayron Lord
he is yours purchased by the blood of
the Living God purchased by Jesus Christ
and so father we thank you for him Bea
demitria is praying for her family that
they would come closer to you Lord so
bless he'll touch save and deliver in
that life and father Kila Mahia is
asking about starting a small group to
pray over the telephone Lord God and
maybe someone else saw that and that was
an idea in their mind to use the phone
for small group prayers we thank you for
this in Jesus name and we're praying for
Michael who just finished his bible
study on the state of the Dead is having
some trouble understanding it Lord we
pray for the spirit of wisdom and
Revelation that his eyes would be open
to understand your truth we pray for the
spirit of truth that would reveal truth
to his soul in Jesus name your word says
that a man can receive nothing except to
be given to him from heaven we can talk
to with black and blue in the face Lord
God and and and but nothing we say is
Ever Enough Lord only the anointed word
of the Living God can break down the
walls around the heart and so we just
pray Lord in Jesus name that you will
pull down those walls around his heart
and so father help him to know you Lord
God in Jesus name and actors box said
that there are strongholds that are
keeping her children from coming to know
you and we pray Lord that you just pull
those strongholds down
Lord we want to pray for sdnb host Lord
I saw that and and as a and as a virtual
Church Lord many of us could show some
Hospitality in various ways and this may
be a way you speak to someone to give
someone rise to church or someone has a
spare room in their home or someone that
has a a gift at at at helping out in
some way that they would get on that
list Lord and say well Lord all I have
and all that is mine is mine only
because I'm in Christ Jesus these things
belong unto you father show me how to
use them for your glory because soon and
very soon the Earth and all these
elements will be burned up Lord so let
us use them now while we can Lord God
and send forth Lord our Treasures into a
place where moth and rust cannot eat
them up and they will not be destroyed
by fire in Jesus name thank you for
Cheryl Smith Lord who is praying uh for
salvation and a job for her daughter and
a home Lord father God her rent is going
up $400 a year Lord I know many of us
are experiencing some of that stuff we
pray that you make room for her Lord and
bless her and heal her in Jesus name
sister emene Wright is praying for her
husband Willie who had a stroke but you
showed Mercy because we weren't even
aware that the stroke happened but God
you had mercy and so we thank you and
now brother Willie's in this hospital
and then we want to pray for his
roommate sometimes you take us in a
storm Lord God for other folks Lord God
that storm might have nothing to do with
us it might be somebody else right there
need to be blessed and so we pray for
that roommate we may have never even
known about that roommate had this thing
not happened and so save this brother
don't know his name don't know his
circumstances don't know his situation
don't know what's going on with that
roommate but we pray for that roommate
today in Jesus glorious name father
thank you so much for Jay who's seeking
to find his purpose in the body of
Christ and for his life Ivon is praying
for her husband Lindy and her children
and their unborn child she says they're
under spiritual attack and so father we
pray put a hedge of protection around
them and Camp your angels about them
Father your words says when the enemy
comes in like a flood the spirit of the
Lord will lift up a standard against
them so let no weapon formed against
this family prosper in Jesus name sister
Jackie Carr is reminding us to pray for
Brother Rick that he would continue to
heal and speaking of Rick I want to pray
for our beloved Rick Lord God H uh uh
brother Rick who did so much great work
with our Bible workers program him and
his wife his bride Julie I pray for them
today Lord that you would bring healing
and comfort into their hearts get them
into a place Lord God in lives when they
continue to be the precious fruitful uh
ministers that you have called them to
be may they just know an abiding peace
and joy beyond what makes sense God get
them that crazy peace oh Lord that
surpasses understanding in Jesus Glory
his name thank you for this precious
family Lord God and Nicole is also
praying for a house and a job close to
her elderly parents and and family who
needs her help Cat Flores is asking for
prayer Sister Janet sister Sharice
Henley is praying for her father-in law
dealing with Dementia Lord sister Sylvia
sadonna who's uh you've allowed me to be
able to reach out to her son's in prison
she's praying about her asthma neck and
back pain from arthritis and on and on
he must increase is reminding us to pray
for London who's having witch Fest on
November 18th the same day that we're
doing
Outreach Lord in the name of Jesus your
word says where sin abounded Grace does
much more abound and so the the enemy
wants to have witchfest on the same day
we doing Outreach I pray in Jesus name
that the Son of God be manifested in
such a way that all the enemy's Works be
destroyed that there be confusion in
their ranks Lord God in Jesus glorious
name somebody get saved there and come
to know Jesus May somebody come to the
realization that this what am I even
doing here I need to be somewhere I need
to be seeking Jesus and so we pray stir
up your spirit in the midst of that
thing father in Jesus glorious name and
so Lord God also for Ang Angela Angela
georgees praying for her 16-year-old
grandson Lord who has allowed the devil
to have his way in his life Lord we just
pray have mercy on this young precious
soul lord God and thank you for bringing
him to our awareness today and we've
prayed today Lord such a long prayer
list so much going on as our first lady
reminded us Lisa Clark Nicole is praying
for Nicole who's an ICU and Angela who's
been diagnosed with cancer and she's
praying about her her witness today and
so father we thank you that you've heard
these prayer requests each and every one
even the ones I didn't even mention and
didn't get around to Lord we thank you
that you know what they are you know our
needs before we even ask and so father
as we prepare to hear this word from
your manservant today make our hearts
attentive make our minds alert Lord May
our eyes be sharp may we listen and hear
what thus saith the Lord God in Jesus
name and may this word be nourishment to
our souls Lord father may we take it and
apply it to our lives to your glory and
to your honor in Jesus name
amen
amen amen amen what a powerful song and
what a perfect song for the message that
you are about to hear
today forgive me how many of you have
often prayed that prayer Lord forgive me
for my failures forgive me for self
often getting in the
way I want to invite you to pray with me
today as uh we are preparing to hear a
message a word from the Lord that I
believe will be a powerful
blessing to you so let's pray Heavenly
Father we're asking today Lord that you
would please speak to us in a very
special way Lord let your word be
glorified
today and may those that are watching
those that are
listening may they understand the
power of your
love and the power of prayer we ask this
in Jesus name amen amen we are going to
be talking today about the power of
prayer and uh in fact as we go to the
screen uh you will see that we're going
to be looking at a case study for this
subject of prayer a case study from The
Book of Revelation does prayer really
work that's the question on the table
today does prayer really work and yes
you read that right we're going to be
looking at the seven trumpets of
Revelation that is going to be our case
study and I just want to ask if you have
ever asked yourself or even wondered
aloud man does prayer really really work
well I want you to check this out
because as we begin our study today
we're going to go to the book of uh
Matthew and we're going to see something
very powerful here remember uh Jesus is
is in the Garden of Gethsemane he is
about to be crucified and he's got
several of his disciples with him and
he's asking them to to pray with him but
they keep falling
asleep and so Jesus uh comes back to
them several times and you read this in
Matthew 26:41 where he says watch and
pray that you enter not into into
temptation the spirit indeed is
willing but the flesh is weak the spirit
is willing but the flesh is weak week
and I want you to understand that that
these words spoken by Jesus are crucial
words we need to understand that we may
desire to do the right thing but unless
we are fortified with
prayer the
Flesh in one sense he's saying the flesh
is weak but in another sense he's saying
the flesh is strong and if we don't
submit to prayer if we don't uh uh uh uh
commune with our heavenly father if we
don't commune with Jesus the power of
the holy spirit will not work through us
to overcome the flesh put a one in the
chat if you're following so far this is
why the Bible tells us about the armor
of God in the book of Ephesians I want
you to notice it with me with me the
book of
Ephesians we're going to go to Ephesians
chapter 6 and note with me beginning
with verse 11 the Bible says put on the
whole armor of God that you may be able
to stand against the Ws of the
devil for we wrestle not against flesh
and blood but against principalities
against Powers against the rulers of the
darkness of this world against spiritual
wickedness in high
places wherefore take unto you the whole
armor of God that you may be able to
stand withstand in the evil day and
having done all to stand stand therefore
having your loins G about with truth and
having on the breastplate of
righteousness and your feet shot with
the preparation of the gospel of peace
reading
on above all take the shield of Faith
wherewith you shall be able to quench
all the fiery darts of the wicked and
take the helmet of salvation and the
sword of the spirit which is the word of
God now I want you to focus in on this
verse right here Verse 18 says praying
always with all prayer and supplication
in the spirit and watching there unto
with all perseverance and supplication
for All
Saints the Bible here is telling
us that prayer is an essential weapon
for the people of God which brings us
back to the question does prayer really
work does prayer really do we have any
evidences that prayer actually works
evidence in history that prayer actually
works and this is why beloved we're
going to take a look at the Book of
Revelation for our case study to answer
this question now I need you to
understand
something this whole sermon today
is to bring to you the power of one
verse now y'all are not going to see
that verse till the very end of the
sermon but everything that I'm about to
share with you from this point forward
is is is is to amplify is to set the
stage for you to see the power behind
this one
verse this is going to give you Hope
just start putting it in the chat if
you're excited put a seven in the chat
this is going to give you hope this is
going to help you to see that yes God
does answer prayer and when you
understand all of that that as the
context for this one verse it's going to
change everything for you so are y'all
ready let's go let's go we're going to
the Book of Revelation The Book of
Revelation and we're going to go to
chapter 8 verse 2 now we're going to
spend most of our time in the Book of
Revelation because we're going to be
dealing with the seven trumpets found in
Revelation chapter 89 10 and
11 and so beginning with Revelation
chapter 8 verse2 the Bible
says John speaking here it says and I
saw seven angels which stood before God
and to them were given seven
trumpets and another angel came and
stood at the altar having a golden
sensor and there was given unto him much
incense that he should offer it with the
prayers of All Saints upon the golden
altar which was Before the
Throne the Bible continues on and the
smoke of the incense which came with the
prayers of the Saints ascended Ed up
before God out of the Angel's hand verse
five and the angel took the sensor and
filled it with fire of the Altar and
cast it into the Earth and there were
voices and thunderings and Lightnings
and an earthquake all right so here's
what I want y'all to get so far okay uh
uh the the the the picture that we see
in Revelation chapter 8 which is an
introduction to the seven trumpets so
this incense rising up out of an angel's
hands with with with the prayers of the
Saints and so whatever is happening here
it involves the prayers of the Saints
and now listen carefully in
answer to the prayers of the Saints we
see fire coming down from God out of
Heaven are y'all with me so far in this
picture in this scene we see prayers of
the same sa going up and we see fire
falling in answer to the prayers of the
Saints put a one in the chat if you're
with me so
far all right I see you all following me
now let's go ahead and move on so what
we want to do here is ask ourselves a
simple question first of
all what what do trumpets symbolize in
the Bible uh what were they used for
because we need to understand this if
we're going to understand the
significance of the blowing of the
trumpets in Revelation chapter8 there
are seven trumpets that are blown what
do these trumpets symbolize let's go
back to the screen and I want you to
note with me we're going to go to a
couple places to see this we'll go to
Revelation I'm sorry we'll go to Numbers
chapter 10 and verse two the Bible says
here God speaking uh instructing the
children of Israel and speaking through
Moses said this make thee Two Trumpets
of silver of a whole piece shalt thou
make them thou sh th that thou mayest
use them for the calling of the assembly
and for the journeying of the camps all
right so if I were to ask you what
according to numbers is the purpose of
the blowing of the trumpet your answer
would be oh Pastor the blowing the
trumpet symbolizes it was a symbol it
was something used to to call the people
of God together and to tell them to
advance to move forward okay so number
one please write the sound if you're
taking notes the trumpet signify the
children of Israel continuing on their
Journey when the trumpet blew it was a a
call to move forward are y'all with me
so far all right so far so good let's go
to the next slide and I want you to
notice here numbers chap 10:9 and if you
go to war in your land against the enemy
that oppresseth you then shall you blow
an alarm with the trumpets and you shall
be remembered before the Lord your God
and you shall be saved from your enemies
all right so if you're taking notes
you're going to be writing down two
things so far number one trumpets
symbolize God's people moving forward
and number two trumpet symbolize God's
people being saved from their
enemies are y'all with me so far all
right excellent let's keep moving let's
keep moving we're going to go back to
the
screen and I want you to notice Joshua
chapter 6 verse5 which tells us yet
another story regarding trumpets this is
when they are Marching around Jericho
right and I want you to notice what
happens here in Joshua chapter 6
verse5 it shall come to pass that when
they when they make a long blast with
the Ram's Horn and when you hear the
sound of the trumpet all the people
shall Shout with a great shout and the
wall of the city shall
what fall down flat and the people shall
Ascend up every man straight way before
him so once again we're seeing here that
when the trumpets were blown one
particular story in the Old Testament
shows that when the trumpets were blown
the city of the enemies
fell let's put this together so far
number one trumpet symbolize moving
forward number two trumpet symbolize
being saved from your enemy number three
trumpet symbolize the enemy opposition
falling all right come on we got one
more one more we're going to go to the
Book of Judges chapter 7 this is the
story of Gideon yet another story
dealing with trumpets and you'll
remember that Gideon was told to go
forth with his 300 men they go forth to
fight the enemy they blow the trumpet
and notice with me Judges chapter 7
verse 21 they stood every man in his
place round about the camp and all the
host ran and cried and fled watch
this and the 300 blew the trumpets and
the Lord set Every Man's sword against
his fellow even throughout the
throughout all the host so what I want
you to see here is that when the
trumpets were blown not only did it
symbolize God's people moving forward
not only did it symbolize the enemies of
God's people falling before them but it
also symbolized that they would turn
their weapons upon
themselves please keep these things in
mind because you're going to see the
significance of this as we come to
understand what these seven trumpets in
the Book of Revelation are talking about
so now I want to ask you a
question because we we've got to kind of
figure out okay well when did this event
happen when is it that we can think of
saints praying in the Bible their
prayers going up and then Fire coming
down in answer to the prayers of the
Saints and if y'all are thinking you got
the answer I know you got it because
this OCC heard on the day of Pentecost
come on y'all let's go there let's go
there I want y'all to check this out
we're talking about the power of prayer
the Bible says in Acts chapter 2 verse
one and when the day of Pentecost was
fully come they were all with one Accord
in one place and suddenly there came a
sound from Heaven as of a rushing Mighty
Wind and it filled all the house where
they were sitting verse four or verse
three and there appeared unto them
clothing tongues like as of
fire and it sa upon each of them what do
you have here what do you have going on
you have saints praying you have saints
praying and as their prayers are going
up the response to their to their
prayers going up is
fire coming
down I need yall catch the significance
of this because what we're about to
see is a chronological case study of God
answering prayer now y'all remember what
happened right this is when the the
church is given the gift of
tongues because God has commissioned
them to take the gospel into all the
world so they have a mission they are
supposed to be moving forward say that
with me someone moving forward
forward with the
gospel now here's what's so significant
keep that in mind here's what is so
significant
because Peter stands up to preach on
this day of
Pentecost and if you remember he quotes
from a particular book remember they
think oh these guys are drunk what we
can't even what are they saying and then
Peter says hey we're not drunk notice
what he says here notice what he says go
back to the screen Peter quotes from The
Book of
Joel here is what he
quotes he says this is that which is
spoke which was spoken by the prophet
Joel listen to
this it shall come to pass in the last
days sayith God I will pour out my
spirit upon All Flesh and your sons and
your daughters shall prophesy and your
young men shall see visions and your old
men shall dream dreams and on my
servants and on my handmaids I will pour
out in those days of my spirit and they
shall
prophesy and I will show wonders in the
heavens and signs in the earth beneath
blood and fire and Vapor of smoke the
sun shall be turned into darkness and
the moon into blood before the great and
notable day of the Lord come now let me
ask y'all a
question how many of you if you were
there on the day of Pentecost would have
been like Peter what are you talking
about we don't see any blood we don't
see the sun getting dark we don't see
any of this stuff what are you talking
about maybe as you read the verse now
you're asking a question why would Peter
be even quoting from The Book of Joel
what is so significance about about this
I want you to note beloved how Joel
chapter 2
begins this is the book that Peter is
quoting from under the inspiration of
the Holy
Spirit notice how the chapter that he's
quoting from
begins come on
y'all come on somebody somebody needs to
put a one in the chat for me if y'all
are catching
this the chapter begins blow ye the
trumpet in Zion and sound an alarm in my
Holy Mountain let all the inhabitants of
the land tremble for the day of the Lord
cometh for it is nigh at hand a day of
darkness and of gloominess a day of
clouds and of thick Darkness as the
morning spread upon the mountains a
great people and a
strong there has not been ever the like
neither shall there be any more after it
even to the years of many generations a
fire
lock this in you guys lock this
in this is the chapter that Peter is
quoting from and this chapter is going
to explain to us that Peter was not
referring to literal blood and literal
Darkness he was saying something that he
was hoping would trigger the memories of
the people that he's talking to his own
people listen to what Joel chapter 2
goes on to
say a fire div farth before them and
behind them a flame burneth the land is
as the Garden of Eden before them and
behind them a desolate Wilderness yay
and nothing shall Escape them what I
want y'all to catches
this
Peter Peter is is warn he's he's telling
them listen
Israel if you do not accept the
Messiah an army is coming to destroy our
nation that's why Peter is referring
back to Joel chapter 2 so the question
we need to ask is very simple well what
army could Peter have possibly been
talking about this this description of
the sky being darken and all these
calamitous things happening were were a
description of the coming destruction of
Jerusalem put a one in the chat if y'all
are
Following come on there's something very
important this is key I need y'all to
get this let's go back to the screen and
and I want you to follow along so so it
says that before them was was like the
Garden of Eden but behind them the land
would be
desolate nothing shall Escape them verse
four the appearance of them is as the
appearance of horses and as Horsemen so
shall they run verse 5
like the noise of Chariots upon the top
of mountain shall they leap like the
noise of a flame of fire that devour its
stubble and as a strong people set in
battle array so he is clearly talking
about an army that is
coming before their faces the people
shall be much pained all faces Shall
Gather Blackness they shall run like
Mighty Men they shall climb the wall
like Mighty Men of War they shall March
everyone on his ways and they shall not
break their ranks the Earth shall Quake
before them and the heavens shall
tremble and the sun and the moon shall
be dark and the Stars shall withdraw
their shining and the Lord shall utter
his voice before his array before his
army for his Camp is very great for he
is strong that executed his word for the
day of the Lord is great and very
terrible who can abide it Joel 2:15 blow
the trumpet in Zion sanctify a fast call
a solemn assembly gather the people
sanctify the congregation assemble the
elders gather the children and those
that suck the breasts let the bridegroom
go forth out of his chamber and the
bride out of her closet let the priests
the Ministers of the Lord weep between
the porch and the Altar and let them say
spare thy people oh Lord and give not
thine Heritage to reproach that the
Heathen should rule over them wherefore
should they say among the people where
is their God Peter is clearly warning
here of a in impending Invasion a
military Invasion but he's using
symbolic
language so so in the Book of Joel
chapter 2 verse2 he goes on to say but I
will remove from AAR off from you the
northern Army and will drive him into a
land Barren and desolate with his face
toward the East sea and his hinder part
toward the utmost sea and his stink
shall come up and his ill Savor shall
come up because he has done great things
and I will restore to you the years that
the Locust has eaten the cankerworm and
the caterpillar and the Palmer worm my
great Army which I sent among you for a
nation is come up upon my land strong
and without number whose teeth are as
the teeth of lion and he has the cheek
teeth of a great Lion now what is God
saying here God is basically saying
listen if my people repent I will drive
this Army from
you so he's laying out Peter is
reminding Israel he's saying to Israel
listen something is coming Upon Our
Nation and if we repent if we if we pray
pray remember the trumpets if we
pray and seek the Lord's
face he will turn this thing away from
our
nation
well what happens
what happens we
know in Joel chapter
1119 the Bible says in the Lord oh Lord
to thee will I cry for the fire has
devoured the pastures of the Wilderness
the flame has burned all the trees of
the field he's talking about the
impending destruction of Jerusalem he's
going back to Joel and he's bringing all
these things to the people's mind and
then notice this did Israel
listen to the warnings given by the
early church the early followers of
Christ they did not and in fact in Acts
7:58 we find the stoning of the first
Christian martyr Stephen the Bible says
uh Bible says in Joel or Acts chapter
7:58 and he said behold I see the
heavens opened and the son of man
standing at the right hand of God then
they cried out with a loud voice and
stopped their ears and ran upon him with
one Accord and they cast him out of the
city and stoned him and the witness laid
down their feet at a young man's feet or
lay down their clothes at a young man's
feet whose name was Saul y'all get the
story right this is where Stephen is
stoned and in effect in effect Israel
has
rejected the
pleadings of
God they stoned Stephen calling upon God
and and they stoned Stephen calling upon
God and saying Lord receive my spirit
and
so we
have the
first Christian martyr being martyred
by God's Own professed
people they've declared themselves
enemies of the early
church setting this Foundation I need
y'all to catch this now we're going
going back to the first trumpet all
right so so notice with me what trumpet
number one says first trumpet Revelation
8 ver7 the first Angel sounded and there
followed hail and fire mingled with
blood and they were cast upon the earth
and the third part of the trees was
burnt up and all the green grass was
burnt up
now I'm gonna ask you a question
we already saw that trumpets
symbolize first of all the trumpets are
blown in answer to what put it in the
chat for me
please the trumpets are blown in answer
to the prayers of the
Saints that's number
one so when the trumpets are blown we
can expect several things number one it
is
God telling his people to do
what to go forward number two it will
represent the fall of the enemies of
God's people are y'all with
me number three it'll represent the
enemies of God's people turning their
weapons upon one another and watch this
all of this in answer to
prayer so so let's ask a question y'all
let's ask the question I want you to
watch this who is the first enemy of the
church the early church who is the first
enemy of the early church because if we
can get the answer to that then we know
what this first trumpet is dealing
with
Beloved the first enemy of the
church was Israel the professed people
of God they were the ones persecuting
and attempting to stop the spread of the
Gospel the the nation that rejected the
Messiah not all individuals in there but
the nation that rejected the Messiah
they became the the the primary opposers
of the
Gospel now you'll remember that Jesus
used the symbol of a fig tree remember
what the Book of Joel said y'all
remember the Book of Joel is talking
about a coming Army that's going to
desolate that's going to burn down
everything in front of it and please
come back with me to that first trumpet
look and the first Angel sounded and
there followed hail and fire mingled
with blood and was cast upon the earth
and the third part of the trees was
burnt up and all the green grass was
burnt up I need y'all to see this
because Jesus used the Fig Tree to
symbolize
Israel when he saw a fig tree in the way
he came to it and found nothing thereon
but leaves only and he said unto it let
no fruit grow on thee henceforth Forward
Forever and presently the Fig Tree
withered away and when the disciples saw
they marveled saying how soon is the fig
tree withered away I need y'all to catch
this everyone you
see in answer to
prayer in answer to prayer in in in an
effort to to to to get the gospel out
the early church is trying to get the
gospel to go into all the world but but
his own professed people are standing as
an obstacle before them and what does
God do in answer to prayer he says we're
moving them out the
way we're going to move this nation out
the way in order for God's message to
advance The Book of Ezekiel chapter 20
verse 46 son of man set thy face toward
the South and drop Thy word toward the
South and prophesy against the forest of
the south field and say to the forest of
the South hear the word of the Lord thus
sayi the Lord God behold I will Kindle a
fire in thee it shall devour every Green
Tree in thee and every dry tree the
Flaming Flames shall not be quenched and
all the faces of the South to the north
shall be burned therein you see God was
trying to let me say it this way the the
the this
first
trumpet is the
punishment of God upon the enemies of
the
Gospel the Bible says in Isaiah 40:6 the
the voice said cry and he said what
shall I cry all flesh is grass and all
the goodliness thereof is the is as the
flower of the field the grass withereth
and the flower fadeth because the spirit
of the Lord bloweth upon it surely the
people is as grass this is the first
trumpet beloved it is the fall of the of
Jerusalem in 70 AD it is the destruction
of Jerusalem and watch this who
destroyed
Jerusalem it was the Romans
the same two groups that came together
to be a party to Christ's crucifixion
end up turning their swords on one
another and the Romans destroy Jerusalem
and in this destruction the Christians
who were Christian Jews Christians were
able to escape and and take the gospel
Advance the
gospel and you want to ask the question
does prayer
work does prayer
work Beloved the answer is yet we have
the evidence listen
prayer
prayer is what allowed the early
Christian Church to advance past their
enemy in order to spread the
gospel come on let's keep moving let's
keep moving the fall of Jerusalem watch
this
the fall of Jerusalem's enemies the fall
of Jerusalem and their enemies turn
their sword turning their sword upon one
another is the Fulfillment of that first
trumpet well what about the second
trumpet the Bible says here and the
second Angel sounded and as it were a
great Mountain burning with fire was
cast into the sea and the third part of
the sea became blood and the third part
of the creatures which were in the sea
had and had life died and the third
third part of the ships were destroyed
now remember we have already seen here
that these trumpets are not talking
about literal fire and literal blood
this is symbolic language and the pace
was set for us when Peter himself quoted
from The Book of
Joel and and what we're seeing here is
that the first trumpet Was the removal
of the first obstacle of the early
church which was the Jewish
Nation so now we got to ask ourselves a
simple question which is this who is the
second enemy of the people of God after
Jerusalem has been moved out the way and
the gospel is going forward who now is
the primary enemy of the people of god
let's go back to the screen I want to
show you something here very quickly
about mountains listen to this I want
you to see what a mountain symbolizes in
the scriptures in Jeremiah 51:4 the
Bible says and I will Render unto
Babylon and to all the inhabitants of
Cala all their evil that they have done
in Zion in your sight say the Lord watch
this behold I am against thee Oh
destroying Mountain say the Lord which
destroyeth all the Earth and I will
stretch out mine hand upon thee and roll
thee down from the rocks and will make
thee a burnt Mountain
so please get this a burning Mountain s
symbolizes a Fallen
Nation a Fallen
Nation so you might ask okay pastor well
well what does this burnt mountain in
this second trumpet symbolize well
remember what we said right if a trumpet
if the blowing of the trumpet represents
the removing of God's enemies then we
know that all we got ask the question
who was the next enemy of the people of
God and the answer is the Rong Roman
Empire the Roman Empire they were
persecuting God's people during the
early centuries of the of the church and
listen to this y'all because this is
absolutely mind-blowing watch this watch
this in the Book of Matthew remember we
had just read Matthew 21 now in the
morning as he returned into the City and
was hungry he saw the fig tree right and
came to it and found nothing there on
but leaves only and said unto it let no
fruit grow on thee henceforth forever
and presently the fig tree within away
we already saw that this fig tree was a
symbol of
Jerusalem God was saying look Jerusalem
has borne no fruit it's going to be
destroyed watch
this and when the disciples saw it they
marveled saying how soon is the Fig Tree
withered away and watch what Jesus's
next words are oh
man watch what Jesus's next words are
y'all remember what the second trumpet
is a burning mountain is cast into the
sea symbolizing the fall of a kingdom of
a power of a Nation what is Jesus's next
words after they Marvel Jesus said watch
this Jesus answered and said unto them
verily I say unto you if you have faith
and doubt
not you shall not only do this which is
done to the fig tree
but also if you shall say unto this
mountain be thou removed and be thou
cast into the sea it shall be
done yeah somebody needs to put put a
five in the chat if y'all are catching
this the second look this fig tree being
cursed is the symbol of Jerusalem being
removed out of your way way so that the
gospel can advance the disciples like
whoa they don't understand what Jesus
saying but they're like whoa look at the
F Tre and Jesus says ver I saying to you
if you have faith and say to this
mountain be thou removed it shall be
done and listen y'all we got to ask
ourselves a question what were the
prayers of the Saints during this time
period where they were being persecuted
by Rome father we want to get this
message out into the world but the there
is an obstacle before us and the Lord
says
I've heard your
prayer trumpet number two is blown
listen
y'all
Rome was brought down by prayer I just
need to stop right here for a second
y'all some now y'all been like well
where you going with this pastor listen
to me you're asking the question is
prayer powerful is prayer effective
listen y'all
Rome was was brought
down by prayer y'all are trying to stop
the spread of the Gospel I'm going to
remove you out of the
way Rome that burning mountain is cast
into the sea you know that Seas
represent peoples Nations multitudes and
tongues and that's exactly what Rome
broke down into peoples Nations
multitudes and
tongues Barbarian
tribes beloved God answers pray if I
were to stop the sermon right here I
would say to you right
now God answers prayers but we're not
done
yet because there are more trumpets to
come let's go back let's go back and
again we're going to ask ourselves a
question we're going to ask ourselves a
question who is the second enemy of the
church and we saw the answer to that was
the Roman Empire so watch this the fall
of J the fall the the first trumpet
represented the fall of Jerusalem the
second trumpet the fall of the Roman
Empire and by the way how did Rome fall
yes they turned their swords upon one
another they turn their swords upon one
another oh
man y'all need to understand
this y'all need to understand
this
listen ROM Falls and now we have a third
trumpet so the third trumpet reads like
this and the third Angel sounded and
there fell a great star from Heaven
burning as it were a lamp and it fell
upon the third part of the rivers and
upon The Fountains of waters and the
name of the star is called wormwood and
the third part of the waters became
wormwood and many men died of the waters
because they were made bitter so now we
got to ask ourselves a question okay H
and beloved listen I want y'all to see
how this is broken down right because
now we got to ask ourselves a question
okay so if we're following the pattern
the first enemies of Rome would
represent of of the church would
represent Jerusalem that city was
removed out of the way the second
enemies of church would represent Rome
that city was moved God they were moved
out of the way so that the message could
advance so now we got to ask ourselves
one simple question who after the fall
of Rome who became the new enemies of
God's
people and you you are right I I I can
pretty much guess what y'all about to
put in the chat right because it was the
papal system it was the
Roman Catholic Church that began
persecuting persecuting the people of
God who refused to acknowledge the pope
as God who refused to do Penance all
those things they began to be attack
they are now the new enemy so now we
know listen to me now now we know that
trumpet three trumpet four trumpet five
trumpet six at least those next four
trumpets are going to be dealing with
the
downfall or we might even say the deadly
wounding of this
church now listen if y'all are have not
followed me in prophetic understanding
before and you're you're you're hearing
this for the first time you might be
like how papacy what go back and watch
some other videos but for those of you
who who are who who who are familiar I'm
not going to take a whole lot of time to
explain this but I need y'all to catch
this these next trumpets are all dealing
with bringing about the the or exposing
if you will the papal system for what it
is which would ultimately lead to its
fall so come on let's break this down
very quickly so so we're gonna go back
to the screen we're going to go back to
the screen who is the third enemy of the
church it is a religio political power
it called the papacy papal R and I want
you to note this third trumpet then is a
punishment upon apostate
Christianity the apostate Church of the
Dark Ages now you say how how because
remember let's go back to that trumpet
it says that the word the waters uh this
um the third Angel sounded and there
fell a great star from Heaven burning as
it were and it fell upon the parts of
the rivers and the fountains of waters
that's where we drink from that's where
people drink from and what's Happening
Here Is God is
poisoning the
religious aspects of the church if you
will remember this is a religio
political power what God is doing here
is he's Leading Men to see something is
the matter with the water the water that
this church is offering it's causing men
to die people were beginning to have
their eyes open to the apostasy and the
error being taught within the system and
this is where we get the beginning of
the Reformation people coming on the
scene like w cliff and others who are
like wait a minute something's wrong
here this would be the H think of the
wal denans this is where we we're gonna
find that that that people began to
realize something is wrong with the
remember water is drinking water is a
symbol of the gospel God is now
revealing there's something wrong with
this drinking water he's exposing the
religious corruption of this system it's
the same thing listen to me watch this
let's go back to the screen a and I want
you to note here I want you to
note U behold Amos chapter 811 behold
the days come save the Lord God that I
will send a famine in the land not a
famine of bread nor thirst for water but
of hearing the words of the Lord and
they shall Wander from sea to Sea and
from the north even to the east they
shall run to and fro to seek the word of
the Lord and shall not find
it in those days shall the fair virgins
and the young men faint for
thirst so so this third trumpet as it
were signified a a an Awakening if you
will something is wrong with this system
that is claiming to serve God the same
thing with the fourth with the fourth
angel or the fourth trumpet the fourth
Angel sounded and the third part of the
sun was smitten and the third part of
the moon and the third part of the Stars
so as that the third part of them was
darkened and the day Shone not forth
third part of it and the night likewise
in other words God is doing the same
thing here he's bringing he's allowing
the darkness of this system to be
revealed so that men would begin to say
wait a minute something's wrong with
this system in fact in Isaiah chapter 8
verse chapter 5:20 it says w unto them
that call evil good and good evil that
put Darkness for light and light for
darkness that put bitter for sweet and
Sweet for
bidder woe unto
them what God is doing here is he's
bringing he's revealing the corruption
the spiritual corruption and bankruptcy
of this system so that God's people
could see and go wait a minute
something's wrong here they they are not
who they profess to be this system is
not what it professes to be and this was
it would would in part lead to the
deadly wounding of this papal
system the these are the roots of the
Protestant Reformation and what is God
saying I want you to advance I want you
to move forward I'm going to move this
system out of your way so that you can
take the gospel into the whole world now
I want you to check sou because there's
still three other
trumpets there's still three other
trumpets I want you to note with me I
want you to note with
me
Revelation Revelation chapter n
Revelation chapter 9 now remember here's
what we just saw the
papacy is a relig political system
trumpets number three and four are
revealing the corruption within the
religious aspect of this system but now
trumpets number five and six are going
to deal with the political or military
aspect of this system note with me
Revelation 9 verse one and the fifth
angel sounded and I saw a star fall from
Heaven onto the Earth and to him was
given the key of the bottomless pit and
he opened the bottomless pit and there
arose of smoke out of the pit as the
smoke of a great furnace and the Sun and
the air were darkened by reason of the
smoke of the pit and there came out of
the smoke Locust upon the Earth and unto
them was given power as the Scorpions of
the Earth have power and it was
commanded them that they should not hurt
the grass of the earth they should not
hurt the grass of the earth neither any
green thing neither any tree but only
those men which have not the Seal of God
in their foreheads now let me pause for
a second let me just come back here for
a
second so I'm G ask yall a
question um and and we're almost there
we're almost done we're we're almost to
that verse that is going to blow your
mind but let me ask you a
question if we know we know that in the
Book of Joel an army just like this was
described and it's described in a sense
of God bringing punishment
upon those who who are opposing his
message so we know that in in Revelation
chapter chapter nine this Army of locust
is not really an army of locust it's an
army of people but now the question is
who are these Army of people coming
for who are they coming for who is this
Army of
people well we know that the enemies of
God's people during this time represent
the papal system
so God is going to allow God is going to
bring another group of people to begin
conflict with the
papacy in order to
give the
reformers
time to get the message
out now I don't know if you know this
history or
not but we're talking about
the Muslim
armies we're talking about the
Crusades I want you to understand that
the
papacy was at a point where they were
trying to totally Stamp Out the
Protestant Reformation but just around
this time they began being attacked by
Muslim armies and they had to turn their
attention and I should say this all this
was a war that was going on for some
time but they ultimately had had to turn
their entire attention and resources to
deal with the Muslim threats and Martin
Luther himself
said that were it not for the Muslim or
the Turkish power engaging with the
papacy protestantism would have been
wiped out
now this is trumpet number five beloved
and trumpet number six which is talking
about the same Army in two different
phases we're not going to spend time to
go into that because this message today
is not so much about prophecy being
fulfilled this message today is to help
you understand something absolutely
mindblowing that the gospel is where it
is in the world today because of the
prayers of the Saints God in answer to
the prayers of the Saints
removed Jerusalem in 70 AD removed the
Roman Empire in the 3 Century ad removed
the papacy after that 1260 year period
known as the Dark Ages gave it a deadly
wound to give God's people time to read
and understand that final message which
was to go into all the world all these
trumpets these six trumpets beloved
represent God answering the prayers of
the Saints by the
way the Turkish Empire the Muslim Army
the Muslim empire what was it a religio
political power so what does God do he
takes one religio political power to war
against another religio political power
in essence they're turning their swords
on one another giving God's people
time giving the Protestant Reformation
time to grow and to
advance beloved we can trace it through
history how prayer
literally moved
Nations so now I'm going ask y'all a
question we get we're we're we're right
about there y'all we are right about
there I'm gonna ask yall a question
we're not going to go through we're not
going to go through all the rest of the
the sixth uh trumpet but I just need
y'all to see something here right I need
y'all to catch
this let's go back to the
screen and I want you to check this
out on we're going to we're just going
to let's go let's go let's go here we go
chapter number five and
six the rise of
Islam and their attack upon the
papacy now now please not
this within this seventh trumpet within
this sixth trumpet we also have the
French Revolution which is in essence
what brought about the deadly wound of
the papacy Revelation 11 is found right
there right after Revelation 9
Revelation 10 it's all in the
trumpets so so watch this y'all ready
here's the seventh angel and the seventh
angel sounded and there were great
voices in heaven saying the kingdom of
this world are become the kingdoms of
our Lord and of his Christ and he shall
reign forever and ever so I got a
question to ask you I if the seventh
trumpet brings about the kingdom of Our
Lord then the question is who is the
final enemy of God's
people who are the final enemies of
God's people because where they are the
seventh trumpet brings about their fall
and if we just saw that the seven
trumpet the kingdoms of this world are
become the kingdoms of Our Lord then
guess what it is the kingdoms of this
world that are the enemies of God's
people they are the F everybody comes
together to fight against the people of
God those that keep the Commandments of
God and have the testimony of Jesus in
fact we could let me let me restate it
this way who are the final enemies of
God's people
Babylon
Babylon watch this y'all watch
this the first trumpet the fall of
Jerusalem the second trumpet the fall of
Rome the third trumpet the fall of the
papacy the fourth trumpet I'm sorry the
third fourth fifth and sixth trumpet the
fall of the papacy we know that the
papacy receives a deadly wound but that
deadly wound would be healed they're
gonna come back and become and be and be
that mystery mystery Babylon revived
along with apostate protestantism and
the entire world the seventh trumpet
beloved is the ultimate fall of
Babylon
prayer brought down the fall of
Jerusalem prayer brought down the fall
of Rome prayer brought down the fall of
the papacy prayer is GNA bring down the
fall of Babylon now I got to ask you a
question what mountain stands in your
way I know I know my sermon is about to
end I I need I needed to demonstrate to
you the power of the prayers of the
Saints rising up and God answering
through these trumpets God answering
saying my people I'm I want you to
advance my people I'mma move the
obstacles out of your way now I'm gonna
ask you a question again what
obstacle stands in your
way perhaps the biggest obstacle that
stands in our way is
self is self
but what I want you to see beloved is
that if
God can move
Nations through
prayer he can move you out of your
way yes he
can yes he can are you mightier than a
nation were you bigger than Rome did you
have more power than
Rome you're not mightier than a
nation beloved God can move not here is
a text y'all here is a
text here it
is Micah
7:19 he will turn again he will have
compassion upon us he will
subdue our
iniquities can y'all can y'all put a
seven in the chat for me please
he will subdue if he subdued Jerusalem
if he subdued Rome if he subdued the
papacy if he's going to subdue Babylon
at the end of time moving these enemies
out of the way as a result of the
prayers of the Saints do you not think
that he can subdue your iniquities he
can move your sins just as he cast that
burning Mountain into the sea can he not
take your sins and cast it into the
depth of the
sea beloved if God is able if God
through prayer if God through the
prayers of the Saints moved
Nations what
sin in your
life can he not
move what sin in your life can he not
forgive and cast it into the sea what is
what obstacle in your life can he not
remove so that you may
Advance with the
purpose of being a light in your
neighborhood a light in your family a
light in the
world does prayer
work I just need you to look at the
history
his we have
evidence not anecdotal evidence biblical
prophetical historical
evidence that God answers
prayers that prayers can move
mountains and bring about the removal of
Nations and so if prayer can do all that
beloved what can prayer not do in your
life what can prayer not
do regarding those
obstacles that are before
you so my wife likes to call these
trumpet prayers cuz she she's heard me
say this before and and once it clicked
for her she was like ah I'm going to
start praying trumpet prayers trumpet
prayers let's start praying trumpet
prayers
believing I want you to understand that
you
know these prayers were going up over
time it wasn't like Just One Day prayer
and then God answered they had to
persevere in
prayer beloved let us persevere in
prayer let us begin to pray trumpet
prayers if that's your desire put that
one in the chat help me to pray trumpet
prayers and help me to believe that when
I pray Lord forgive me of my sin remove
this Sin from me that God does it help
me to know that when I pray Lord REM
self is an obstacle in my way right now
please remove self let us have the faith
that just as God said you can say to
this mountain be thou moved into the sea
so so so God can move the obstacle that
stops you from coming closer to
him Heavenly Father we thank you
Lord for showing
us how much you are
invested in the gospel advancing to the
whole
world and that anything that stands in
the way of the Salvation of souls you
will
remove
Lord teach us to have that
Faith to say to the mountains before us
be thou removed into the sea and believe
that they shall be
moved grant us the
patience and the faith to use the weapon
of prayer and believe in the power of
prayer thank you Lord for speaking to
our hearts today
in Jesus name we pray amen may God bless
you uh we're going to put up in the link
uh the the we're going to put up in the
chat the link for alter live we invite
you to join us for the discussion
afterward um please look out for the
Bible study uh uh questions that will
come up for this uh sermon for the small
group for those of you that are in small
groups look out for that that'll be uh
up on Mighty networks uh on Sunday and
may God bless you I pray that this
message has moved your heart and that it
has planted faith in your in your in
your inner being to know that God does
in fact answer prayers may God bless you
and have a great
Sabbath thank you for joining us today
if this is your first time worshiping
with us please check out our website at
Living mana. Church we are not just here
for Sabbath service we have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health physical health weekly prayer
service Financial Health and proving the
existence of God it is our desire that
our programming will continue to bless
you please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the Gospel of Jesus
[Music]
Christ